<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_michal-jamroz.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2016-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Deep learning for image segmentation</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pydata-warsaw-group/deep-learning-for-image-segmentation.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mateusz Opala</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-09-28:pydata-warsaw-group/deep-learning-for-image-segmentation.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;#6 PyData Warsaw&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deep learning techniques ignited a great progress in many computer vision tasks like image classification, object detection, and segmentation. Almost every month a new method is published that achieves state-of-the-art result on some common benchmark dataset. In addition to that, DL is being applied to new problems in CV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the talk we’re going to focus on DL application to image segmentation task. We want to show the practical importance of this task for the fashion industry by presenting our case study with results achieved with various attempts and methods.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Representation learning</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pydata-warsaw-group/representation-learning.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Mateusz Opala</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-09-24:pydata-warsaw-group/representation-learning.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;#1 PyData Warsaw&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the last couple of years there’ve been a lot of buzz generated around performance of deep learning algorithms. DeepMind’s AI plays Atari games, Google’s AI recognizes cats on youtube, smartphones are great at speech recognition, and who knows what we’ll read about tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the talk we’re going to show you what’s deep learning about using a couple of practical examples. You’ll see that the state-of-the-art of machine learning is not out of reach of a determined pythonista who doesn’t keep away from math.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>