<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_meg-ray.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Python for N00bs: A cognitive and educational approach</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2018/python-for-n00bs-a-cognitive-and-educational-approach.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Meg Ray</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-10:pycon-us-2018/python-for-n00bs-a-cognitive-and-educational-approach.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will put a new spin on helping complete beginners to use Python. We all tend to teach Python the way that we learned it. However, by applying lessons learned from cognitive science and educational psychology, we can better help a wide range of beginners and open up Python to new audiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The speaker will share examples of successes and failures in teaching Python in several contexts including high school classrooms, the Young Coders program, as well as online and printed curricula. Topics covered will include teaching the command line, helping new programming concepts to “stick,” increasing engagement with abstract concepts, and supporting the independence of new programmers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Python community is an ecosystem built on learning from others and giving back to others. The strategies covered in this talk are useful for creating documentation for new users, writing a book or tutorial, teaching a child or adult, running a workshop, or teaching a class.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Accessible Python Instruction</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2017/accessible-python-instruction.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-10-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Meg Ray</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-28:pycon-uk-2017/accessible-python-instruction.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note, this presentation was re-recorded in a different room on sunday after technical difficulties with the projector curtailed the initial attempt, but is in included in it's original slot here.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This session will be about including secondary students with special educational needs and disabilities in Python instruction in classrooms, after-school clubs, and summer camps. The session will help teachers (including those new to Python) and programmers who teach to design and deliver instruction to students with a range of abilities and needs. The session is informed by my experiences as a special educator, computer science teacher, educational researcher, and teaching coach in the US, and it will include examples from classrooms in which I have worked.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>