<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_erik-romijn.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Helping communities &amp; products thrive by fostering empathy</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pycon-cz-2017/helping-communities-products-thrive-by-fostering-empathy.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Erik Romijn</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-06-09:pycon-cz-2017/helping-communities-products-thrive-by-fostering-empathy.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Empathy is a fundamental part of human interaction. When we
communicate by email or at conferences, or indirectly, when we create
products, events, or do a talk. However, our understanding of other
people is full of error, and worse, bias. This can lead us to make
communities and products that work poorly for people that are
different from ourselves, introduce confusion and misunderstanding,
exclude people unintentionally, and sometimes even cause harm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, our communities are an opportunity to learn as well. To
embrace our diversity, and expand our understanding of other people’s
worlds. To gain understanding of other people’s situations,
experiences and emotions, which can be dramatically different to
ours. And how we can use this to create both products and communities
which work great not only for ourselves, but also those that we more
easily forget about. As creators in tech we have such tremendous
power to create change, but merely our best intentions will not be
enough for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will explore how and why we sometimes have such difficulty
to understand others, and how others can have difficulty to
understand us. We’ll talk about why other people’s experiences,
emotion and perceptions can be so different. Both for the world as a
whole, but also with the speaker’s personal experiences. Finally,
we’ll cover specific ways for us to understand others better, and
associated pitfalls, to make our communities and products happy,
inviting and supportive places.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>All about community panel</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2017/all-about-community-panel.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dr. Russell Keith-Magee</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-04:djangocon-europe-2017/all-about-community-panel.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A discussion about the efforts to have open, and sustainable communities (in economic, physical and emotional sense) and how this reflects on individuals&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>The road to unempathic communities is paved with good intentions</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2017/the-road-to-unempathic-communities-is-paved-with-good-intentions.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Erik Romijn</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-03:djangocon-europe-2017/the-road-to-unempathic-communities-is-paved-with-good-intentions.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our communities are built on communication. We talk directly, by email, chat or at conferences, or indirectly, when we write copy for our products or our events, or do a talk. Especially when not speaking in person, it is incredibly easy and common to introduce confusion and misunderstanding, exclude people unintentionally, and sometimes even cause harm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, our communities are an opportunity to learn as well. To embrace our diversity, and make newcomers feel welcome, for example. To gain understanding of how people’s insecurities and fears can enlarge communication issues, sometimes into serious sources of stress and other negativity. To help people from minorities feel like they belong in our community. But merely our best intentions will not be enough for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will explore how we sometimes fail to communicate what we intended to, and how to improve on that. Specifically, we’ll talk about how to be more aware of how we make others feel, and in the end make our communities happy, inviting and supportive places.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Healthy Minds in a Healthy Community</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2016/djangocon-us-2016-healthy-minds-in-a-healthy-community-by-erik-romijn.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Erik Romijn</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-12:djangocon-us-2016/djangocon-us-2016-healthy-minds-in-a-healthy-community-by-erik-romijn.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Healthy Minds in a Healthy Community by Erik Romijn&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open source communities attract and boast passionate, idealistic people, and many of us invest copious amounts of time and effort to contribute to our projects and support our communities. This underlying emotional attachment can make us more vulnerable to elevated stress, burnout and conflicts. And then there are those of us who also manage mental illness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More often than not, we suffer these struggles in silence, feeling (and fearing) that we’re alone in our trouble. Here, our communities can make a huge difference, by building a positive and safe environment where we can blossom and support ourselves and our peers, and feel included.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The community around Django is already very mindful towards inclusivity, and keeping an eye on the well-being of community members. We have recently launched several new projects to further promote the well-being of our community members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will take a look at open-source communities through the eyes of various mental well-being issues and struggles, and discuss and report on the progress our new initiatives. Hopefully, this will help foster healthy minds in a healthy environment.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Healthy Minds in a Healthy Community</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2016/healthy-minds-in-a-healthy-community.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-03-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-03-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Erik Romijn</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-03-30:djangocon-europe-2016/healthy-minds-in-a-healthy-community.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can find more about this talk on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2016.djangocon.eu/speakers/13"&gt;djangocon.eu&lt;/a&gt;. This video is hosted by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://opbeat.com/community/posts/healthy-minds-in-a-healthy-community-by-erik-romijn-and-mikey-ariel/"&gt;opbeat.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="django"></category></entry><entry><title>A sincere tale of Django, developers and security</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2015/erik-romijn-a-sincere-tale-of-django-developers-at.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Erik Romijn</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-07-10:djangocon-europe-2015/erik-romijn-a-sincere-tale-of-django-developers-at.html</id><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title>Lightning Talks (day 2)</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2010/djangoconeu-lightningtalkssecondday965flv.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-05-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2010-05-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Erik Romijn</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2010-05-25:djangocon-europe-2010/djangoconeu-lightningtalkssecondday965flv.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><category term="lightning talks"></category></entry></feed>