<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_russell-keith-magee.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Building a cross-platform native app with BeeWare</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2018/building-a-cross-platform-native-app-with-beeware.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Russell Keith-Magee</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-12:pycon-us-2018/building-a-cross-platform-native-app-with-beeware.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever wanted to write a GUI application you can run on your laptop? What about an app that you can run on your phone? Historically, these have been difficult to achieve with Python, and impossible to achieve without learning a different API for each platform. But no more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BeeWare is a collection of tools and libraries that allows you to build cross-platform native GUI applications in pure Python, targeting desktop, mobile and web platforms. In this talk, you'll be introduced to the BeeWare suite of tools and libraries, and see how you can use them to develop, from scratch, a GUI ChatBot application that can be deployed as a standalone desktop application, a mobile phone application, and a single page webapp - without making any changes to the application's codebase.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="beeware"></category><category term="cross-platform"></category><category term="gui"></category></entry><entry><title>Autopsy of a slow train wreck: The life and death of a Django startup</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2017/autopsy-of-a-slow-train-wreck-the-life-and-death-of-a-django-startup.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Russell Keith Magee</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-08-14:djangocon-us-2017/autopsy-of-a-slow-train-wreck-the-life-and-death-of-a-django-startup.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;DjangoCon US 2017 - Autopsy of a slow train wreck: The life and death of a Django startup by Russell Keith-Magee&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone knows the story: armed with nothing more than a laptop and a dream, a couple of plucky geeks decide to take on the world: disrupting, innovating, and subverting their way to success. In just a few short months, they take a ramshackle collection of software and turn it into a money-printing factory that enables them to drive off into the sunset in gold-plated Lamborghinis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it isn’t always like that. In fact, it usually isn’t. Venture Capitalists (VC’s) make their investments betting that 15 out of 20 businesses they invest in will outright fail, 4 will maybe get a payoff, and 1 will be a massive success. We always hear about the 1 - the Facebooks, the Instagrams, the WhatsApps. But we very rarely hear about the 15 that don’t succeed. And that’s only counting the VC-funded companies - there are many other companies that never make it past hobby stage, or live a short, privately funded life on the back of consulting income before being quietly shut down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a case study of one such a failure - TradesCloud. What went right? What went wrong? And what you can learn from TradesCloud’s mistakes if you’re contemplating starting a business of your own?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2017.djangocon.us/talks/autopsy-of-a-slow-train-wreck-the-life-and-death-of-a-django-startup/"&gt;https://2017.djangocon.us/talks/autopsy-of-a-slow-train-wreck-the-life-and-death-of-a-django-startup/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>