<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_analytics.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2017-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Data Plumbing 101 - ETL Pipelines for Everyday Projects</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2017/data-plumbing-101-etl-pipelines-for-everyday-projects.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Eberhard Hansis</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-25:pycon-de-2017/data-plumbing-101-etl-pipelines-for-everyday-projects.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eberhard Hansis&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been writing code for more than two thirds of my life, mostly for scientific computing and data analysis. In the past couple of years, I have worked on a range of different data science projects, all using Python at their core. During this time, I repeatedly was tasked with making data usable by joining multiple sources into a clearly defined data model. Once you have done that, it is amazing how much real-life value you can generate with little more than a bit of statistics and visualization. The world is full of underused data, let’s change that!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no data science without ETL! This presentation is about implementing maintainable data integration for your projects. We will have a first look a ‘Ozelot’, a library based on Luigi and SQLAlchemy that helps you get started with building ETL pipelines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;ETL, the hard way&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are starting a new data science project, and you can’t wait to perform some machine learning magic. However, before getting to ML, you have to deal with its ugly sibling: ETL. Extracting, transforming and loading data (or, more generally, data integration) is an indispensable first step in almost any data project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your project you will, most likely, have to extract data from various sources, clean it, link it and prepare it to your needs. You will start writing a first data integration script for some part of the process, then a second, then a third. At some point you will write an ugly ‘master’ script to keep your 17 import scripts in check and run them in just the right order. When you come back to the code later, you will have a hard time deciphering what you did and why, and what format the output data is in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pipelines to the rescue&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Implementing a proper data integration pipeline and a well-defined data model helps document your data flows and makes them traceable. More importantly, it simplifies the ETL development process, because it lets you easily re-run the whole process or parts of it. And you will have to modify and re-run your ETL, because your code changes, your output requirements change or the data changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I propose a setup for building maintainable data integration pipelines for everyday projects. This setup is embodied by ‘Ozelot’, my brand-new Python library for ETL. It is based on Luigi for pipeline management and SQLAlchemy as ORM layer. Ozelot gives you core functionality to quickly start building your own solution, including an ORM base class, database connection management and Luigi task classes that play nice with the ORM. It comes with extensively documented examples that walk you through various aspects of data integration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The proposed setup works well for many small- to medium-sized projects -- projects, for which you previously might not have implemented a proper data integration pipeline. For big-data projects or those requiring live streaming data you probably want to consider alternative solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Core principles of data integration&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taking one step back, I propose the following core principles for maintainable data integration:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any and all data manipulation happens in the pipeline, in a single code base.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The pipeline represents all dependencies between data integration tasks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each task has a method for rolling back its operations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data is loaded into a single database, in a clearly defined, object-based data model that also encodes object relationships.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The whole process is fully automatic and thereby reproducible and traceable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will discuss why I think that these principles are important, and how they are reflected in the proposed setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recorded at&lt;/strong&gt; PyCon.DE 2017 Karlsruhe: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://de.pycon.org/"&gt;https://de.pycon.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video editing&lt;/strong&gt;: Sebastian Neubauer &amp;amp; Andrei Dan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tools&lt;/strong&gt;: Blender, Avidemux &amp;amp; Sonic Pi&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="data-science"></category><category term="analytics"></category><category term="python"></category></entry><entry><title>Data Science Best Practices : From Proof of Concepts to Production</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2017/data-science-best-practices-from-proof-of-concepts-to-production.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Yasir Khan</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-25:pycon-de-2017/data-science-best-practices-from-proof-of-concepts-to-production.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yasir Khan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yasir Khan is working as a Data Science Manager. He has nearly 12 years of experience in consulting and R&amp;amp;D domains. He obtained his PhD in Applied Machine Learning and has been invited as a speaker at several leading international forums and conferences. He has nearly 12 research articles and journals to his credit and book chapters published by Cambridge University Press.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In his spare time he loves flying WWII aircrafts at a local aeroclub and is an avid scuba diver. He is also an investor in 2 technology startups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This presentation will benefit the audience as it brings forward the practical issues in the industry today as we move towards industrializing data science algorithms. We will discuss the best practices around organization, methodology and tools to integrate a data science project into production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the industry understands the importance of Data Science for transforming businesses an interesting trend is arising. We have started seeing a widening gap &amp;amp; increasing difficulty to move teams from Proof of Concepts to Production. Apart from searching for the best data scientists, the industry is now looking for answers to organize &amp;amp; federate the data teams around practical business use cases. In this talk, Yasir Khan will provide an overview of the bottlenecks, and hurdles involved in a practical data project. While citing lessons learned from industry, this presentation will focus on important aspects such as business centric, data culture, data pipelines, organization, methodology &amp;amp; tools all of which are important but seldom ignored in large corporations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recorded at&lt;/strong&gt; PyCon.DE 2017 Karlsruhe: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://de.pycon.org/"&gt;https://de.pycon.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video editing&lt;/strong&gt;: Sebastian Neubauer &amp;amp; Andrei Dan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tools&lt;/strong&gt;: Blender, Avidemux &amp;amp; Sonic Pi&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="use-case"></category><category term="analytics"></category><category term="python"></category><category term="machine learning"></category><category term="ai"></category><category term="business"></category></entry><entry><title>Effective Data Analysis with Pandas Indexes</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2017/effective-data-analysis-with-pandas-indexes.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alexander Hendorf</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-25:pycon-de-2017/effective-data-analysis-with-pandas-indexes.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pandas is the Swiss-Multipurpose Knife for Data Analysis in Python. In this talk we will look deeper into how to gain productivity utilizing Pandas powerful indexing and make advanced analytics a piece of cake. Pandas features multiple index types. This talk will give you a deep insight into the Pandas indexes and showcase the handiness of special Indexes as the TimeSeriesIndex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recorded at&lt;/strong&gt; PyCon.DE 2017 Karlsruhe: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://de.pycon.org/"&gt;https://de.pycon.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video editing&lt;/strong&gt;: Sebastian Neubauer &amp;amp; Andrei Dan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tools&lt;/strong&gt;: Blender, Avidemux &amp;amp; Sonic Pi&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="machine learning"></category><category term="analytics"></category><category term="data-science"></category><category term="business analytics"></category></entry><entry><title>Flow is in the Air: Best Practices of Building Analytical Data Pipelines with Apache Airflow</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2017/flow-is-in-the-air-best-practices-of-building-analytical-data-pipelines-with-apache-airflow.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dominik Benz</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-25:pycon-de-2017/flow-is-in-the-air-best-practices-of-building-analytical-data-pipelines-with-apache-airflow.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dominik Benz&lt;/strong&gt; (&amp;#64;john_maverick)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dominik Benz holds a PhD from the University of Kassel in the field of Data Mining on the Social Web. Since 2012 he is working as a Big Data Engineer at Inovex GmbH. In this time, he was involved in several projects concerned with establishing analytical data platforms in various companies. He is most experienced in tools around the Hadoop Ecosystem like Apache Hive and Spark, and has hands-on experience with productionizing analytical applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apache Airflow is an Open-Source python project which facilitates an intuitive programmatic definition of analytical data pipelines. Based on 2+ years of productive experience, we summarize its core concepts, detail on lessons learned and set it in context with the Big Data Analytics Ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Motivation &amp;amp; Outline&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating, orchestrating and running multiple data processing or analysis steps may cover a substantial portion of a Data Engineer and Data Scientist business. A widely adopted notion for this process is a &amp;quot;data pipeline&amp;quot; - which consists mainly of a set of &amp;quot;operators&amp;quot; which perform a particular action on data, with the possibility to specify dependencies among those. Real-Life examples may include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Importing several files with different formats into a Hadoop platform, perform data cleansing, and training a machine learning model on the result&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;perform feature extraction on a given dataset, apply an existing deep learning model to it, and write the results in the backend of a microservice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apache Airflow is an open-source Python project developed by AirBnB which facilitates the programmatic definition of such pipelines. Features which differentiate Airflow from similar projects like Apache Oozie, Luigi or Azkaban include (i) its pluggable architecture with several extension points (ii) the programmatic approach of &amp;quot;workflow is code&amp;quot; and (iii) its tight relationship with the the Python as well as the Big Data Analytics Ecosystem. Based on several years of productive usage, we briefly summarize the core concepts of Airflow, and detail in-depth on lessons learned and best practices from our experience. These include hints for getting efficient quickly with Airflow, approaches to structure workflows, integrating it in an enterprise landscape, writing plugins and extentions, and maintaining it in productive environment. We conclude with a comparison with other analytical workflow engines and summarize why we have chosen Airflow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Questions answered by this talk&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the core concepts of Apache Airflow?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How can Airflow help me with moving data pipelines from analytics to production?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which concepts of Airflow make it more slim and more efficient compared to Apache Oozie?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How can I specify dynamic dependencies at runtime between my analytical data processing steps?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which facilities does Airflow offer to enable automation and orchestration of analytical tasks?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How can I extend the built-in facilities of Airflow by writing Python plugins?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;People who benefit most from this talk&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data Scientists who are looking for a slim library to automate and control their data processing steps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data Engineers who want to save time debugging static workflow definitions (e.g. in XML)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Project leaders interested in tools which lower the burden of moving from analytics to production&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hadoop Cluster administrators eager to save cluster resources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recorded at&lt;/strong&gt; PyCon.DE 2017 Karlsruhe: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://de.pycon.org/"&gt;https://de.pycon.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video editing&lt;/strong&gt;: Sebastian Neubauer &amp;amp; Andrei Dan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tools&lt;/strong&gt;: Blender, Avidemux &amp;amp; Sonic Pi&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="workflow"></category><category term="data pipeline"></category><category term="data-science"></category><category term="analytics"></category></entry><entry><title>Large-scale machine learning pipelines using Luigi, PySpark and scikit-learn</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2017/large-scale-machine-learning-pipelines-using-luigi-pyspark-and-scikit-learn.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alexander Bauer</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-25:pycon-de-2017/large-scale-machine-learning-pipelines-using-luigi-pyspark-and-scikit-learn.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alexander Bauer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alexander Bauer holds a Ph.D. in computer science. He has around 10 years industry experience, currently leading a team of data scientists at Lidl, one of the largest global discount supermarket chains. He is a Kaggle Master and regular speaker at the Frankfurt Predictive Analytics Meetup. He believes in agile software development practices and promotes Python as a primary language for data science applications in production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For prescriptive analytics applications, data science teams need to design, build and maintain complex machine learning pipelines. In this talk, we demonstrate how such pipelines can be implemented in a robust, scalable and extensible manner using Python, Luigi, PySpark and scikit-learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data science teams working on real-world prescriptive analytics applications face the challenge to design, build and maintain considerably complex machine learning pipelines on a daily basis. Such pipelines include parsing data from multiple data sources, extracting relevant predictive features, executing training, validation, prediction steps and finally optimizing actions to meet desired business outcome so that they can be shared and visualized to business users. In this talk, we demonstrate how such pipelines can be implemented end-to-end in a robust, scalable and extensible manner using Python, Luigi, PySpark and scikit-learn. We will share our lessons learned from using this framework in a real-world demand forecasting use case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recorded at&lt;/strong&gt; PyCon.DE 2017 Karlsruhe: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://de.pycon.org/"&gt;https://de.pycon.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video editing&lt;/strong&gt;: Sebastian Neubauer &amp;amp; Andrei Dan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tools&lt;/strong&gt;: Blender, Avidemux &amp;amp; Sonic Pi&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="data-science"></category><category term="analytics"></category><category term="python"></category><category term="machine learning"></category></entry><entry><title>Master 2.5 GB of unstructured specification documents with ease</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2017/master-25-gb-of-unstructured-specification-documents-with-ease.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Andreas Schilling</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-25:pycon-de-2017/master-25-gb-of-unstructured-specification-documents-with-ease.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dr. Andreas Schilling&lt;/strong&gt; is Senior Software Engineer at eXXcellent solutions. In his job, he helps customers to develop software solutions from the early stage of defining the particular requirements to developing information systems which meet their needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before working at eXXcellent solutions Andreas Schilling studied Information Systems at the University of Bamberg focusing on distributed systems and information management. Thereafter, he pursued his PhD and studied collaboration dynamics in open source projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How Do you kick start a project which is based on 2.5 GB files of unstructured specification documents? To answer this question, we present our lessons learned from developing a Python based knowledge management tool which provides a lightweight and intuitive browser frontend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we present lessons learned from and practical advice on how to deal with a large body of specification documents in your next project. We introduce our approach as well as code excerpts from our powerful toolset to transform a large set of unstructured and partially corrupt specification documents into structured JSON Files. Finally, we showcase a simple, yet powerful Javascript frontend which requires no additional infrastructure to present the compiled artefacts in an intuitive and responsive user interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In particular this talk covers the following topics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to make use of pywin32 to access layout and content information from partially corrupt .doc and .docx files and create simple JSON files with UTF-8 encoding.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identify and categorize signal words in your specification.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use pandas to compile content based recommender functionality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use networkx and py2cytoscape to visualize call sequences and semantic relationships in your specification.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Present the compiled artefacts and identified relationships in an easy-to-use and lightweight Javascript browser interface without any additional infrastructure (i.e. no webserver and no database server).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recorded at&lt;/strong&gt; PyCon.DE 2017 Karlsruhe: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://de.pycon.org/"&gt;https://de.pycon.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video editing&lt;/strong&gt;: Sebastian Neubauer &amp;amp; Andrei Dan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tools&lt;/strong&gt;: Blender, Avidemux &amp;amp; Sonic Pi&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="networkx"></category><category term="pandas"></category><category term="visualization"></category><category term="knowledge-management"></category><category term="analytics"></category><category term="use-case"></category><category term="python"></category><category term="business"></category></entry><entry><title>Sport analysis with Python</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2017/sport-analysis-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Thuy Le</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-25:pycon-de-2017/sport-analysis-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give an example data of the IoT sport case for instance the information of football match of a team (the positions, velocities of each player with are recorded in every 20 millisecond).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We use Python to analysis and processing data (calculate the match time, analyst the activities of each player such as time in the bench, time in the pitch, ... )&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We use Tableau to visualize data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recorded at&lt;/strong&gt; PyCon.DE 2017 Karlsruhe: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://de.pycon.org/"&gt;https://de.pycon.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video editing&lt;/strong&gt;: Sebastian Neubauer &amp;amp; Andrei Dan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tools&lt;/strong&gt;: Blender, Avidemux &amp;amp; Sonic Pi&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="devops"></category><category term="analytics"></category><category term="data-science"></category><category term="python"></category></entry><entry><title>The Python Ecosystem for Data Science: A Guided Tour</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2017/the-python-ecosystem-for-data-science-a-guided-tour.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Christian Staudt</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-25:pycon-de-2017/the-python-ecosystem-for-data-science-a-guided-tour.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Christian Staudt&lt;/strong&gt; (&amp;#64;C_L_Staudt)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am an independent data scientist with a background in computer science, in-depth in algorithms, data analysis, high-performance computing and software engineering. My current interests include machine learning and data visualization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pythonistas have access to an extensive collection of tools for data analysis. The space of tools is best understood as an ecosystem: Libraries build upon each other, and a good library fills an ecological niche by doing certain jobs well. This is a guided tour of the Python data science ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Python Ecosystem for Data Science: A Guided Tour&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python is on its way to becoming the lingua franca of data science, and Pythonistas have access to an impressive and extensive collection of tools for data analysis. Here, a data scientist needs to see the forest for the trees: The space of tools is best understood as an ecosystem, where libraries build upon each other, and where a good library fills an ecological niche by doing certain jobs well. This talk is a guided tour of the Python data science ecosystem. More than a list of libraries, it aims to provide some structure, classing tools by type of data, size of data, and type of analysis. In our tour, we visit a number of areas, including working with tabular data (numpy, pandas, dask, ...) and graph data (e.g. networkx), statistics (e.g. statsmodels), machine learning (scikit-learn, ...), data visualization (matplotlib, seaborn, bokeh, ...). Aspiring data scientists, and everyone else working with data, should find this useful for selecting the right tools for their next data-driven project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recorded at&lt;/strong&gt; PyCon.DE 2017 Karlsruhe: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://de.pycon.org/"&gt;https://de.pycon.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video editing&lt;/strong&gt;: Sebastian Neubauer &amp;amp; Andrei Dan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tools&lt;/strong&gt;: Blender, Avidemux &amp;amp; Sonic Pi&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="use-case"></category><category term="business"></category><category term="ai"></category><category term="analytics"></category><category term="data-science"></category><category term="python"></category><category term="machine learning"></category></entry><entry><title>Turbodbc: Turbocharged database access for data scientists</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2017/turbodbc-turbocharged-database-access-for-data-scientists.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Michael König</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-25:pycon-de-2017/turbodbc-turbocharged-database-access-for-data-scientists.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Michael König&lt;/strong&gt; (&amp;#64;turbodbc)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Michael is a senior software engineer at Blue Yonder GmbH. He holds a PhD in physics, practices test-driven development, and digs Clean Code in C++ and Python. In the last five years, he invested more money in table tennis gear than in smartphones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python's database API 2.0 is well suited for transactional database workflows, but not so much for column-heavy data science. This talk explains how the ODBC-based turbodbc database module extends this API with first-class, efficient support for familiar NumPy and Apache Arrow data structures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk introduces the open source Python database module turbodbc. It uses standard ODBC drivers to connect with virtually any database and is a viable (and often faster) alternative to &amp;quot;native&amp;quot; Python drivers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Briefly recounting the painful story of how data scientists previously used our analytics database, I explain why turbodbc was created and what distinguishes it from other ODBC modules. Sketching the flow of data from databases via drivers and Python modules to consumable Python objects, I motivate a few extensions to the standard database API 2.0 that turbodbc has made. These extensions heavily use NumPy arrays and Apache Arrow tables to provide data scientists with both familiar and efficient binary data structures they can further work on. I conclude my talk with benchmark results for a few databases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recorded at&lt;/strong&gt; PyCon.DE 2017 Karlsruhe: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://de.pycon.org/"&gt;https://de.pycon.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video editing&lt;/strong&gt;: Sebastian Neubauer &amp;amp; Andrei Dan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tools&lt;/strong&gt;: Blender, Avidemux &amp;amp; Sonic Pi&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="numpy"></category><category term="database"></category><category term="python"></category><category term="data-science"></category><category term="analytics"></category></entry><entry><title>Data Science &amp; Data Visualization in Python. How to harness power of Python for social good?</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2017/data-science-data-visualization-in-python-how-to-harness-power-of-python-for-social-good.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Radovan Kavicky</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-06-30:pydata-berlin-2017/data-science-data-visualization-in-python-how-to-harness-power-of-python-for-social-good.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python as an Open Data Science tool offers many libraries for data visualization and I will show you how to use and combine the best. I strongly believe that power of data is not only in the information &amp;amp; insight that data can provide us, Data is and can be really beautiful and can not only transform our perception but also the world that we all live in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my talk I will primarily focus on answering/offer the answer to these questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why we need data science and why more and more people should be really interested in analyzing data and data visualization? (motivation)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is data science and how to start doing it in Python? (introduction of procedures, tools, most popular IDE-s for Python, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What tools for data analysis and data visualization Python offers? (in each stage of analysis the best libraries will be shown for the specific purpose; as for data visualization we will focus particularly on Bokeh, Seaborn, Plotly and use of Jupyter Notebook and Plotly)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to 'unlock' the insight hidden in data through Python and how to use it to transform not only public administration or business, but ultimately the transformation of the whole society and economy towards the insight &amp;amp; knowledge based? (potential of data science)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open Data, Open Government Partnership, Open Public Administration &amp;amp; all the advantages of Open Data Science &amp;amp; Python. Data-Driven Approach. Everywhere. Now. (the end of talk +vision)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary><category term="python"></category><category term="data-science"></category><category term="data-visualization"></category><category term="analytics"></category><category term="PyData"></category><category term="PyDataBLN"></category><category term="PyDataBerlin"></category><category term="PyDataBA"></category><category term="PyDataBratislava"></category><category term="talk"></category><category term="Data"></category><category term="Bokeh"></category><category term="Social Good"></category><category term="datascience"></category><category term="jupyter"></category><category term="open science"></category><category term="open data science"></category><category term="DataVisualization"></category><category term="data-analysis"></category><category term="analysis"></category><category term="matplotlib"></category><category term="numpy"></category><category term="data wrangling"></category><category term="jupyter notebook"></category><category term="pandas"></category><category term="machine learning"></category><category term="deep learning"></category><category term="Open Data"></category><category term="Citizen Data Science"></category></entry></feed>