<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Taking Django Async</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2018/taking-django-async.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Django Channels project has taken a major turn with version 2.0, embracing Python's async functionality and building applications around an async event loop rather than worker processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doing this, however, wasn't easy. We'll look through some of the techniques used to make Django coexist in this async world, including handing off between async and sync code, writing fully asynchronous HTTP and WebSocket handling, and what this means for the future of Django, and maybe Python web frameworks in general.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Andrew Godwin</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-11:pycon-us-2018/taking-django-async.html</guid><category>django</category><category>async</category><category>django channels</category></item><item><title>API-Driven Django</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2018/api-driven-django.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the web continues to evolve, the demand for data-driven backends matched with rich frontend experiences grows every day. Django comes with a robust templating system and rendering engine, but more and more web applications using Django are just focusing on it’s API abilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if we could have the best of both worlds? What if we could use Django and django-rest-framework to write views that let us prototype quickly using the Django templating system, and have those same views return API responses to rich clients?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, we’ll build a sample data collection and display web application, taking advantage of the ways Django and django-rest-framework work together. The end result will be a web application you could adapt for many kinds of data collection needs, and you’ll come away knowing how to get a rich API and a frontend prototype out of just one Django view.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Philip James</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-10:pycon-us-2018/api-driven-django.html</guid><category>django</category></item><item><title>Beyond Django Basics</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2018/beyond-django-basics.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finished with the official Django getting started guide, and not sure what to do next?  This tutorial has you covered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll extend the blog built in the official guide, using a variety of slightly more advanced Django features.  Topics to be covered include: extending the in-built user model, using the in-built login system, enhancing forms, using view mixins and overriding view methods, and changing up your database backend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With each extension, we'll talk about not just how to use these features but also &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; you'd want to use them.  We'll conclude by talking about other Django features you may want to learn about as you grow more proficient with this versatile framework.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Shauna Gordon-McKeon</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-10:pycon-us-2018/beyond-django-basics.html</guid><category>django</category></item><item><title>Intermediate testing with Django: Outside-in TDD and Mocking effectively</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2018/intermediate-testing-with-django-outside-in-tdd-and-mocking-effectively.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once developers have got the hang of the basics of testing, problems of applying it in the real world soon start to manifest themselves, and common questions come up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What order should I write my tests and code in to avoid wasting time on blind alleys?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If I'm using Mocks in my tests to avoid external dependencies, how do I avoid getting stuck with unwieldy, unreadable tests that don't actually tell me when things have gone wrong?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unit tests vs integration tests vs functional tests, which should I use when, and what are the trade-offs?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial we'll work through an example of using an existing Django codebase, adding a new feature, and experimenting with different testing techniques along the way to illustrate the pros and cons of each&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bottom-up vs outside-in development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;double-loop TDD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;using Mocks to isolate application layers from each other&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;listen to your tests&amp;quot;, and learning to use ugly or convoluted tests as a signal for improving design.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some familiarity with Django is desirable, although skills learned in other web frameworks are transferrable.  By the end, you'll be able to go back to your own projects with practical experience, and a new way of thinking about how to optimise your tests for your own circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Harry  Percival</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-10:pycon-us-2018/intermediate-testing-with-django-outside-in-tdd-and-mocking-effectively.html</guid><category>django</category><category>tdd</category><category>mock</category></item><item><title>Introduction to TDD with Django</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2018/introduction-to-tdd-with-django.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the past few years, automated software testing has moved from being a niche interest to being the default assumption.  This tutorial is an introduction to Test-Driven Development (TDD) for the world of web development in Python using the Django framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tutorial is suitable for people who are new to either testing, or Django, or both, although some basic working knowledge of Python syntax (or programming in another language) is assumed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn about:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unit testing and Functional testing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the Selenium browser automation tool&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python's unittest standard library module&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Django models, views and templates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;testing front-end and back-end code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;refactoring, using tests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the unit-test/code cycle, or Red-Green-Refactor, TDD workflow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and the Testing Goat, Python's unofficial mascot for testing!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come prepared!  You'll need a Python 3.6 virtualenv with Django and Selenium installed.  Detailed instructions are provided &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.obeythetestinggoat.com/book/pre-requisite-installations.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Harry  Percival</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-10:pycon-us-2018/introduction-to-tdd-with-django.html</guid><category>tdd</category><category>django</category></item><item><title>Building Rich Applications with Django and Ember.js</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2012/building-rich-applications-with-django-and-emberjs.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;After several years in the depths of high-performance computing, I returned to the web world a couple years ago and discovered that Django's awesome-to-pain ratio had tipped strongly in it's favor. I've been hooked ever since. As web lead at dotCloud for the past year, I've gotten to work on making Django deployment awesome at DotCloud in San Francisco. I'm now spending more of my time doing developer advocacy -- acting as dotCloud's &amp;quot;customer-in-residence&amp;quot; to ensure the company is producing a product developers love. I maintain and contribute to a number of open source projects: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/gabrielgrant"&gt;https://github.com/gabrielgrant&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, learn how Django and Ember.js can compliment each other: how to integrate them where their functionality overlaps and reconcile the differences where their approaches contradict. Django helps quickly express a data model and handle HTTP requests, but using it alone isn't conducive to building highly-dynamic interfaces. Ember, on the other hand, is a client-side framework designed with precisely these interfaces in mind, but doesn't tackle the server-side at all. Both Django and Ember.js are large, ambitious and opinionated frameworks. This is what gives them their power over their more minimalist colleagues (Flask and Backbone.js, respectively) but because their opinions sometimes differ, it can be difficult to make them play together. In this talk, I'll briefly introduce Ember.js, compare and contrast how Django and Ember.js handle the various layers of an application, and show how to bridge between these two worlds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Topics covered:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ember's interpretation of MVC in Django terms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overlap in functionality: which pieces of each framework to keep, modify and throw away&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compiling Assets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Connecting Ember to Django with Ember-data and Django REST framework&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Gabriel Grant</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2012-09-15:pytexas-2012/building-rich-applications-with-django-and-emberjs.html</guid><category>django</category><category>ember.js</category></item><item><title>A Web App in Four Frameworks</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycascades-2018/a-web-app-in-four-frameworks.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk we take a tour of some Python web frameworks through the lens of an API for the same web application: a simple To Do list. We'll see how the same problems are handled across Django, Flask, Pyramid, and Tornado, and why you might choose one over the rest.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nicholas Hunt-Walker</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2018-01-22:pycascades-2018/a-web-app-in-four-frameworks.html</guid><category>framework</category><category>Django</category><category>Flask</category><category>Pyramid</category><category>Tornado</category></item><item><title>Plugin ecosystems for Python web-applications</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2017/plugin-ecosystems-for-python-web-applications.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Raphael Michel&lt;/strong&gt; (&amp;#64;rami)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I‘m a software developer working with the web for more than ten years and with Python and Django for over four years. I work as a freelancer and maintain multiple open source projects. The most notable Django-based one is pretix, a full-featured and free conference ticketing software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The power of some popular web applications like WordPress comes from a flexible plugin system. This talk will show how to implement such plugin architectures for Python web applications including real-world examples. I'll give examples with Django, but the important bits aren't Django-specific.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is probably common sense by now that modular architectures win over monolithic architectures in a number of ways. Django gives us reusable apps, but just because they are reusable doesn’t mean they automatically integrate nicely with each other and a Python programmer is still required to glue them together. In this talk I will show how to build a rich Django application that provides a well-defined plugin API. The API will allow plugins to seamlessly integrate with the main application. The talk will show various patterns around URL routing, Django‘s signal system and the use of setuptools to provide auto-detection of installed plugins. Installing a plugin should not be much more complicated than a simple pip install.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Django is only used as an example, most parts could be easily transferred to other web frameworks as well. The explained architecture has been in use for some years in the pretix open source project and made it possible to us to grow a rich plugin ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recorded at&lt;/strong&gt; PyCon.DE 2017 Karlsruhe: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://de.pycon.org/"&gt;https://de.pycon.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video editing&lt;/strong&gt;: Sebastian Neubauer &amp;amp; Andrei Dan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tools&lt;/strong&gt;: Blender, Avidemux &amp;amp; Sonic Pi&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Raphael Michel</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-25:pycon-de-2017/plugin-ecosystems-for-python-web-applications.html</guid><category>django</category><category>python</category><category>web</category></item><item><title>Crash test of Django ORM</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/crash-test-of-django-orm.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The world is swimming in articles and books about Django and Django ORM
itself. All this sources cover only basic use cases of Django ORM
comparing to real world examples. This talk is dedicated to the
proposition to crash test Django ORM 80% of functionalities in 20% of
the time. Also I’m going to show the important features and capabilities
of Django ORM compare to most of SQL features. Traditionally, ORM is
presented in a “bottom-up” fashion, but I would like to propose
approach, on the other hand, is “top-down”. We begin by identifying a
rather short list of standard questions, or precisely types of
questions, that are often asked of relations databases. We then show how
these standard questions are posted in Django ORM, introducing and
motivating the use of its capabilities and features as they become
relevant.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Andrii Soldatenko</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-09:pycon-italia-2017/crash-test-of-django-orm.html</guid><category>django-orm</category><category>performance</category><category>postgresql</category><category>python3</category><category>django</category></item><item><title>Indicizzare e cercare tonnellate di dati con ElasticSearch e Django</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/indicizzare-e-cercare-tonnellate-di-dati-con-elasticsearch-e-django.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cercare in maniera efficente e veloce in grandi quantità di dati risulta
essere, almeno nel mio campo e nelle mie esperienze, un problema
abbastanza diffuso. In questo talk sarà affrontato da un punto di vista
tecnico/sistemistico la parte di indicizzazione di grandi volumi di
dati, le accortenze da avere quando si indicizzano dati in un engine di
search e anlaytics e la parte di monitoring del cluster ELK. Nella
seconda parte invece verrà mostrata l’interazione di una web interface
(Django based) con elasticsearch. Conoscenze necessarie per il talk:
concetti base di serializzazione, restful web services, django&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ernesto Arbitrio</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-09:pycon-italia-2017/indicizzare-e-cercare-tonnellate-di-dati-con-elasticsearch-e-django.html</guid><category>elasticsearch</category><category>json</category><category>Full Text Search</category><category>REST</category><category>django</category></item><item><title>Open edX, soluzione per l'e-learning basata su Django</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/open-edx-soluzione-per-le-learning-basata-su-django.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Open edX è una soluzione open source basata (quasi) interamente su
Django per l’erogazione di Massive Open Online Courses (MOOC). La
soluzione è stata concepita dal Massachusetts Institute of Technology
(MIT) e dalla Harvard University. Anche se al team di lavoro si sono ora
uniti altri nomi illustri come la Stanford University, Microsoft e molti
altri.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In questo talk approfondiremo le funzionalità offerte da Open edX, la
sua architettura e qualche cenno di sviluppo di estensioni e moduli
aggiuntivi.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Davide Corio</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-09:pycon-italia-2017/open-edx-soluzione-per-le-learning-basata-su-django.html</guid><category>Python</category><category>E-learning</category><category>MOOC</category><category>django</category></item><item><title>Digital Analytics Data Aggregation: un case study dal mondo reale utilizzando SQL, NoSQL e Pandas</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/digital-analytics-data-aggregation-un-case-study-dal-mondo-reale-utilizzando-sql-nosql-e-pandas.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I clienti enterprise si trovano sempre più spesso ad avere difficoltà
nel recuperare informazioni essenziali per capire nel complesso dove il
brand sta funzionando e dove invece serve un intervento tempestivo,
perchè sono inondati di dati di dettaglio che spesso non sono facilmente
aggregabili e visualizzabili insieme con frequenza giornaliera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Per rispondere a questa esigenza, in azienda, nel nostro reparto R&amp;amp;D,
abbiamo sviluppato una dashboard che permette a clienti con diversi
brand e properties (siti) di aggregare i principali KPI da monitorare
(sia KPI standard che KPI personalizzati). I KPI sono i key performance
indicators, ovvero metriche che aiutano a valutare le performance).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ma i dati da visualizzare e aggregare, provenienti da diverse fonti
(Google Analytics, Adobe Analytics, tools SEO), hanno strutture diverse
e non è possibile a priori prevedere quali sono le strutture
disponibili.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perciò, in questo talk vedremo insieme come abbiamo gestito questo caso
reale attraverso un mix di tecnologie SQL (MySQL attraverso Django) e
NoSQL (MongoDb), utilizzando i dataframe di Pandas come layer intermedio
attraverso il quale lavorare il dato velocemente.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La soluzione realizzata ci ha permesso di integrare rapidamente nuove
fonti e nuovi KPI, e di gestire volumi elevati di dati (attualmente 200+
siti contemporaneamente) con ottime performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vedremo poi (se rimane tempo) come questi dati vengono forniti
attraverso API Rest (grazie a Django Rest Framework) e consumati
attraverso AngularJS sul client.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vorremmo infine coinvolgervi chiedendovi come avreste gestito questa
difficoltà - non è assolutamente detto che la nostra soluzione sia per
forza quella ottimale!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alessandro Pelliciari</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/digital-analytics-data-aggregation-un-case-study-dal-mondo-reale-utilizzando-sql-nosql-e-pandas.html</guid><category>django-rest-framework</category><category>mongodb</category><category>django</category><category>API Design</category><category>web-development</category><category>angularjs</category><category>mysql</category><category>google-analytics</category><category>pandas</category></item><item><title>Django Rest Framework - Tips&amp;Tricks</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/django-rest-framework-tipstricks.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Developing Web APIs for Django websites have never been so easy.
Starting from a real world use case, I’ll explain why DRF became our
weapon of choice to develop in a fast and easy way all the APIs we need
at Cloud Academy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll start talking about the main benefits that DRF brings to Django
projects, then we’ll use our real world use case to describe the best
practices we use to build fast, secure and maintainable APIs diving into
DRF main features and functionalities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scope of this talk is to explain in a very practical way how DRF can
be integrated into Django projects to build beautiful web APIs. We’ll
use a lot of code examples and performance benchmarks to describe the
various features explored during the talk. No prior experience on DRF is
required but at least some basic knowledge of Django is suggested for
attendees.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luca Zacchetti</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/django-rest-framework-tipstricks.html</guid><category>django-rest-framework</category><category>REST API Frameworks</category><category>API Design</category><category>REST</category><category>django</category><category>optimization</category><category>performance</category></item><item><title>Ricerca full text in Django con PostgreSQL</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/ricerca-full-text-in-django-con-postgresql.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dalla versione 1.10 di &lt;strong&gt;Django&lt;/strong&gt; è presente il modulo che facilita
l’utilizzo del motore di &lt;strong&gt;ricerca full text&lt;/strong&gt; di PostgreSQL. Dal
momento che &lt;strong&gt;PostgreSQL&lt;/strong&gt; è utilizzato in molti progetti Django,
sfruttare il suo motore di ricerca full text permette di avere questa
funzionalità molto facilmente, senza dover configurare prodotti esterni
e senza doversi preoccupare di mantenere sincronizzati i dati tra
differenti sistemi. Vedremo come abbiamo sfruttato questa funzionalità
di ricerca full text in un &lt;strong&gt;progetto reale&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Paolo Melchiorre</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/ricerca-full-text-in-django-con-postgresql.html</guid><category>Full Text Search</category><category>search</category><category>postgresql</category><category>python3</category><category>django</category></item><item><title>Deploy automatizzato di un progetto Python 3/Django con Ansible</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/deploy-automatizzato-di-un-progetto-python-3django-con-ansible.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;La mia applicazione è pronta e funziona senza problemi sulla mia
macchina con il server di sviluppo, ma non ho chiaro come portarla in un
ambiente di produzione. Ci sono parecchi servizi che permettono il
deploy con un solo click, adatti soprattutto a semplici siti, ma essi
non sono pienamente configurabili e nascondono il modo in cui il server
è effettivamente organizzato. Anche se molti usano ingegnose soluzioni
PaaS, vale ancora la pena capire come costruire da zero un ambiente di
produzione con Linux, Python 3, Django e uWSGI. Nel talk questo classico
stack verrà brevemente introdotto e si mostrerà poi come automatizzare
la configurazione e la procedura di deploy con un &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/marco-santamaria/django-%20ansible-deploy"&gt;playbook
Ansible&lt;/a&gt;
che verrà messo a disposizione. Una particolare enfasi verrà data
all’uso di variabili d’ambiente per la configurazione del progetto
seguendo l’approccio delle twelve-factor-app. Inoltre verranno spiegati
i concetti più importanti di Ansible (playbook, ruoli, template, moduli,
inventari).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Marco Santamaria</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/deploy-automatizzato-di-un-progetto-python-3django-con-ansible.html</guid><category>deploy</category><category>devops</category><category>automation</category><category>nginx</category><category>ansible</category><category>best-practices</category><category>django</category><category>uwsgi</category></item><item><title>Presenting pysftpserver: OpenSSH SFTP service with Python</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/presenting-pysftpserver-openssh-sftp-service-with-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever needed to connect to an OpenSSH SFTP server and keep track
of the user activities? Or maybe limit user permissions? Or define
specific callbacks to react to user actions?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;pysftpserver&lt;/em&gt; is an OpenSSH SFTP wrapper, written purely in Python. It
is yet another cool example of what you might already know: how powerful
Python can be while staying extremely simple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk aims at presenting the tool and a few use cases in which it
was harnessed, including one with Django and Django REST Framework. It
requires a good knowledge of Python and Django and understanding the
basics of a SFTP service.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Filippo Morelli</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/presenting-pysftpserver-openssh-sftp-service-with-python.html</guid><category>SFTP</category><category>command-line</category><category>django-rest-framework</category><category>storage</category><category>django</category><category>ssh</category><category>servers</category></item><item><title>Building a startup with Django</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pyconweb-2017/building-a-startup-with-django.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Blueshoe was founded in 2014. Since the beginning of our company we used Python and the web framework Django to build web pages and applications. With respect to technology, there have been many ups and downs in the past 2 ½ years. This is an experience report about building a startup with Django.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Michael Schilonka</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-05-28:pyconweb-2017/building-a-startup-with-django.html</guid><category>django</category></item><item><title>Google AMP for Django</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pyconweb-2017/google-amp-for-django.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What actually is Google AMP, what’s its use case and should I use it? AMP could be a new kind of SEO coming up, even though it isn’t yet. Still it brings some good insights and best practices for web developers. This talk is about the technology, what’s behind it and how you can use it with Django.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Robert Stein</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-05-28:pyconweb-2017/google-amp-for-django.html</guid><category>django</category></item><item><title>Oh, I found a Security Issue</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pyconweb-2017/oh-i-found-a-security-issue.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A talk together with Florian Apolloner&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever thought about what happens when somebody finds a security issue in Django? How does one responsibly disclose the issue? What happens after that? How does the Django team work on it? What happens until a Django security release is published? What comes afterwards?
Also, Django is “reassuringly secure”. Let’s look at the history ;-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll give an insight on how the Django team handles security issues,
which can serve as a guideline and followed in own projects. We'll
will also review the history of Django's security issues to identify
hotspots and areas to look out for.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Markus Holtermann</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-05-28:pyconweb-2017/oh-i-found-a-security-issue.html</guid><category>django</category><category>security</category></item><item><title>Django and the new frontend era</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pyconweb-2017/django-and-the-new-frontend-era.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;React, Ember, Vue - these are just some of the big beasts of the frontend world. How do they fit in a Django world? Is Django still suited for how we are now developing web apps?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I work as Full stack developer so I often jump from Django to frontend frameworks like React and Vue JS. I’d like to share the way we structure Django apps in order to work well with frontend frameworks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Patrick Arminio</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-05-27:pyconweb-2017/django-and-the-new-frontend-era.html</guid><category>django</category></item><item><title>Real-Time Data with Django</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pyconweb-2017/real-time-data-with-django.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;For several years, Rachel Willmer has been searching for the perfect real-time data solution for her Django-based website, Luzme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two most recent candidates under the microscope are Google Firebase (a paid service) and the new Django Channels (free and open source).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rachel shares her experiences of both and compares the relative advantages and disadvantages.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Rachel Willmer</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-05-27:pyconweb-2017/real-time-data-with-django.html</guid><category>keynote</category><category>django</category></item><item><title>To index or not, that's not the question</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pyconweb-2017/to-index-or-not-thats-not-the-question.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Database indexes play a key role in every database query. Hence, it's not a question that you should be able to define them through Django. While you're already kind of able to do that with &lt;cite&gt;dbindex=true&lt;/cite&gt; and &lt;cite&gt;index_together&lt;/cite&gt;, these options are rather limiting. Django 1.11 comes with a new feature to allow you to express your index requirements much more granular.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Markus Holtermann</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-05-27:pyconweb-2017/to-index-or-not-thats-not-the-question.html</guid><category>django</category></item><item><title>Ansible &amp; Terraform for Django: Move Faster, break fewer things</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-se-2017/ansible-terraform-for-django-move-faster-break-fewer-things.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Intro level talk about using Ansible and Terraform together. These tools allow you to provision cloud resources such as Virtual Servers or CDN and to set up your servers with whatever software is needed. This allows to treat infrastructure as code, a cornerstone of DevOps.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ezequiel Golub</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-09-06:pycon-se-2017/ansible-terraform-for-django-move-faster-break-fewer-things.html</guid><category>ansible</category><category>terraform</category><category>django</category></item><item><title>Moving our Django Monolith to Google Cloud</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-se-2017/moving-our-django-monolith-to-google-cloud.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We transitioned our Django monolith from bare-metal to Google Cloud Container Engine (Kubernetes). We will share our findings during this journey.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Arthur Koziel</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-09-06:pycon-se-2017/moving-our-django-monolith-to-google-cloud.html</guid><category>django</category></item><item><title>Flask vs Django</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-es-2017/flask-vs-django.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Flask or Django? Which one is better? We know the answer: it depends!
In RavenPack, we use both frameworks in big projects and for that, we have been dealing with its strengths and weaknesses in a real-world environment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Dario Varotto</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2017 14:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-09-24:pycon-es-2017/flask-vs-django.html</guid><category>flask</category><category>django</category></item><item><title>Fullstack Single Page Applications con Django + Webpack + Vue.js</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-es-2017/fullstack-single-page-applications-con-django-webpack-vuejs.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Veremos cómo montar una app fullstack usando Django y Vue.js con todos los ingredientes necesarios:
- cómo integrar webpack para empaquetar la parte de cliente (Javascript, CSS y otros recursos) a partir de los fuentes
- cómo configurar el entorno de desarrollo para disfrutar de la super productividad que aporta hot-module-reloading en el flujo de trabajo normal
- cómo crear REST endpoints en Django
- cómo gestionar la autenticación de usuarios y las sesiones con Django.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La charla será una demo de cómo crear una app de este estilo de principio a fin.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Javier Abadía</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2017 12:30:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-09-24:pycon-es-2017/fullstack-single-page-applications-con-django-webpack-vuejs.html</guid><category>django</category><category>webpack</category><category>vue.js</category></item><item><title>Exprimiendo el ORM de Django</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-es-2017/exprimiendo-el-orm-de-django.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Muchas veces nos resulta mucho más fácil escribir una consulta a base de datos en SQL plano que lidiar con las limitaciones del ORM de Django, perdiendo así la gran potencia y limpieza que este nos ofrece.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los operadores Q() y F() son, muchas veces, algo que copiamos de la documentación sin entender completamente. Hacer joins simples puede no ser posible, y no hablemos de joins con claves foráneas de más de una columna.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acabamos abusando del método extra() y la clase RawSQL cuando, en realidad, pueden no ser necesarios.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La experiencia nos ha enseñado a sacar el máximo partido de esta funcionalidad y exprimir al máximo sus posiblidades, limitando al máximo la escritura de código SQL plano. Explicaremos cómo, mediante la definición de algunos elementos básicos e intermedios para manipular querysets y la presentación de algunos trucos útiles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Puede que te ahorre un par de consultas a la documentación y que descubras alguna cosa nueva, o simplemente que vuelvas a apreciar el ORM de Django.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Héctor Pablos López</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2017 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-09-24:pycon-es-2017/exprimiendo-el-orm-de-django.html</guid><category>django</category><category>orm</category></item><item><title>Aplicaciones Geográficas con Django</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-es-2017/aplicaciones-geograficas-con-django.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;La 'ubicación' es una de las variables más importantes en cualquier problema, y es una de las más complicadas de manejar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Django - sin ser un servidor geográfico de primera clase - proporciona una buena plataforma para incorporar el &amp;quot;dónde&amp;quot; en nuestras aplicaciones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presentaremos - de forma práctica - las capacidades geográficas de Django (acceso a BB.DD espaciales, consultas geográficas) y sus limitaciones, indicando herramientas complementarias (p.ej. Leaflet) o stacks alternativos.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alicia Pérez</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2017 11:30:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-09-24:pycon-es-2017/aplicaciones-geograficas-con-django.html</guid><category>gis</category><category>django</category></item><item><title>Sysadmin vs Django</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-es-2017/sysadmin-vs-django.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Basado en una historia real xP … se mostrará como es posible desarrollar una webapp con Python afrontando un deadline ajustado y sin experiencia previa en desarrollo frontend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Este proyecto se convirtió en una experiencia altamente gratificante aunque no exenta de escollos, solventados con mayor o menor fortuna. Precisamente estos tips prácticos serán los que protagonicen la charla con un objetivo claro, intentar facilitar el transito del novato al mundo Django.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alguno de los puntos que trataremos:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;La elección del framework con Django como opción natural.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;¿Cómo me monto mi entorno de desarrollo? (docker-compose)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;¿Qué motor de BBDD elijo?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Estructuración del proyecto&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;settings.py y .env&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Esquema de urls&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Autenticación / Registro&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Modelos y Vistas ... tal para cual&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Django Rest Framework o el Santo Grial de nuestro Backend&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cómo diseñar nuestro Frontend, el mundo de los templates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gestión de permisos .. cada oveja con su pareja&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JS, Bootstrap , ¿eso que es lo es?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ya tengo mi web ¿ahora qué? Estrategias de despliegue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nos iremos con una app en el portátil y con suerte quedareis tan enganchados como yo al universo Django.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Juan Diego Godoy Robles</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2017 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-09-24:pycon-es-2017/sysadmin-vs-django.html</guid><category>django</category></item><item><title>Tu web está lista, ¿lo sabe Google?</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-es-2017/tu-web-esta-lista-lo-sabe-google.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Llevas meses peleándote con el código, luchando con bugs… Y por fin terminas el proyecto y lo haces público. Pero no entra nadie...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;¿Se te olvida algo? ¿Estás seguro de que has hecho todo lo posible en cada fase del desarrollo para que la web se posicione en Google? ¿Has elegido las URLs correctas o los títulos adecuados? ¿Te acordaste de bloquear la indexación de los entornos de prueba?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Beatriz González</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-09-23:pycon-es-2017/tu-web-esta-lista-lo-sabe-google.html</guid><category>seo</category><category>django</category></item><item><title>Desplegando webapps con Django en Kubernetes</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pyday-galicia-2017/desplegando-webapps-con-django-en-kubernetes.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">José Corral</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 17:40:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-06-10:pyday-galicia-2017/desplegando-webapps-con-django-en-kubernetes.html</guid><category>pyday</category><category>Galicia</category><category>django</category><category>kubernetes</category></item><item><title>DjangoCon 2008: Chairman Opening Keynote</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2008/djangocon-2008-chairman-opening-keynote.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Conference Chair Robert Lofthouse, Jacob Kaplan-Moss and Leslie Hawthorn welcome attendees to DjangoCon 2008.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.djangocon.org"&gt;http://www.djangocon.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Robert Lofthouse</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2008-09-06:djangocon-us-2008/djangocon-2008-chairman-opening-keynote.html</guid><category>Django</category><category>djangocon</category><category>djangocon2008</category></item><item><title>DjangoCon 2008: Code Writing and Design</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2008/djangocon-2008-code-writing-and-design.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Malcolm Tredinnick&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.djangocon.org"&gt;http://www.djangocon.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Malcolm Tredinnick</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2008-09-06:djangocon-us-2008/djangocon-2008-code-writing-and-design.html</guid><category>Django</category><category>djangocon</category><category>djangocon2008</category></item><item><title>DjangoCon 2008: Django on Jython</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2008/djangocon-2008-django-on-jython.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speakers: Jim Baker and Leo Soto&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.djangocon.org"&gt;http://www.djangocon.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jim Baker</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2008-09-06:djangocon-us-2008/djangocon-2008-django-on-jython.html</guid><category>Django</category><category>djangocon</category><category>djangocon2008</category></item><item><title>DjangoCon 2008: GeoDjango</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2008/djangocon-2008-geodjango.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Justin Bronn&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.djangocon.org"&gt;http://www.djangocon.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Justin Bronn</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2008-09-06:djangocon-us-2008/djangocon-2008-geodjango.html</guid><category>Django</category><category>djangocon</category><category>djangocon2008</category></item><item><title>DjangoCon 2008: High Performance Django</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2008/djangocon-2008-high-performance-django.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: David Cramer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.djangocon.org"&gt;http://www.djangocon.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">David Cramer</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2008-09-06:djangocon-us-2008/djangocon-2008-high-performance-django.html</guid><category>Django</category><category>djangocon</category><category>djangocon2008</category></item><item><title>DjangoCon 2008: Inside the ORM</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2008/djangocon-2008-inside-the-orm.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Malcolm Tredinnick&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http:/www.djangocon.org"&gt;http:/www.djangocon.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Malcolm Tredinnick</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2008-09-06:djangocon-us-2008/djangocon-2008-inside-the-orm.html</guid><category>Django</category><category>djangocon</category><category>djangocon2008</category></item><item><title>DjangoCon 2008 Keynote: Adrian Holovaty &amp; Jacob Kaplan-Moss</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2008/djangocon-2008-keynote-adrian-holovaty-jacob-kaplan-moss.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Adrian Holovaty and Jacob Kaplan-Moss deliver keynote address &amp;quot;Django's Future&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.djangocon.org"&gt;http://www.djangocon.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Adrian Holovaty</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2008-09-06:djangocon-us-2008/djangocon-2008-keynote-adrian-holovaty-jacob-kaplan-moss.html</guid><category>Django</category><category>keynote</category><category>djangocon</category><category>djangocon2008</category></item><item><title>DjangoCon 2008 Keynote: Cal Henderson</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2008/djangocon-2008-keynote-cal-henderson.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cal Henderson delivers keynote address: &amp;quot;Why I Hate Django&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.djangocon.org"&gt;http://www.djangocon.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cal Henderson</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2008-09-06:djangocon-us-2008/djangocon-2008-keynote-cal-henderson.html</guid><category>Django</category><category>keynote</category><category>djangocon</category><category>djangocon2008</category></item><item><title>DjangoCon 2008 Keynote: Guido van Rossum</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2008/djangocon-2008-keynote-guido-van-rossum.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Guido van Rossum, creator of Python, on Django and Google App Engine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.djangocon.org"&gt;http://www.djangocon.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Guido van Rossum</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2008-09-06:djangocon-us-2008/djangocon-2008-keynote-guido-van-rossum.html</guid><category>Django</category><category>keynote</category><category>djangocon</category><category>djangocon2008</category></item><item><title>DjangoCon 2008 Keynote: Mark Ramm</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2008/djangocon-2008-keynote-mark-ramm.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mark Ramm delivers keynote address: &amp;quot;Building a better framework - A Turbogears guy on what Django should learn from Zope.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mark Ramm</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2008-09-06:djangocon-us-2008/djangocon-2008-keynote-mark-ramm.html</guid><category>Django</category><category>keynote</category><category>djangocon</category><category>djangocon2008</category></item><item><title>DjangoCon 2008 Keynote Questions: State of Django</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2008/djangocon-2008-keynote-questions-state-of-django.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jacob Kaplan-Moss &amp;amp; Adrian Holovaty answer attendee questions following their &amp;quot;State of Django&amp;quot; Keynote&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.djangocon.org"&gt;http://www.djangocon.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jacob Kaplan-Moss</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2008-09-06:djangocon-us-2008/djangocon-2008-keynote-questions-state-of-django.html</guid><category>Django</category><category>keynote</category><category>djangocon</category><category>djangocon2008</category></item><item><title>DjangoCon 2008 Lightning Talks</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2008/djangocon-2008-lightning-talks.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Various speakers give short talks on Django and related topics.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Various speakers</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2008-09-06:djangocon-us-2008/djangocon-2008-lightning-talks.html</guid><category>lightning talks</category><category>Django</category><category>djangocon</category><category>djangocon2008</category></item><item><title>DjangoCon 2008 Panel: Django in Journalism</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2008/djangocon-2008-panel-django-in-journalism.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moderator:
Adrian Holovaty&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Panelists:
Matt Waite, Maura Chace, Matt Croydon, Ben Welsh&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.djangocon.org"&gt;http://www.djangocon.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Adrian Holovaty</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2008-09-06:djangocon-us-2008/djangocon-2008-panel-django-in-journalism.html</guid><category>Django</category><category>panel</category><category>djangocon</category><category>djangocon2008</category></item><item><title>DjangoCon 2008 Panel: Django Success Stories</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2008/djangocon-2008-panel-django-success-stories.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moderator:
Jacob Kaplan-Moss&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Panelists:
Matt Croydon, Michael Greer, Joshua Jag Ginsberg, Leah Culver, Andy McCurdy, Jason Yan&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jacob Kaplan-Moss</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2008-09-06:djangocon-us-2008/djangocon-2008-panel-django-success-stories.html</guid><category>Django</category><category>panel</category><category>djangocon</category><category>djangocon2008</category></item><item><title>DjangoCon 2008 Panel: Django Technical Design</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2008/djangocon-2008-panel-django-technical-design.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moderated by Michael Trier&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Panelists: Jacob Kaplan-Moss, Adrian Holovaty, Simon Willison, James Bennett, Malcolm Tredinnick&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.djangocon.org"&gt;http://www.djangocon.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Michael Trier</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2008-09-06:djangocon-us-2008/djangocon-2008-panel-django-technical-design.html</guid><category>Django</category><category>panel</category><category>djangocon</category><category>djangocon2008</category></item><item><title>DjangoCon 2008 Panel: Schema Evolution</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2008/djangocon-2008-panel-schema-evolution.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moderator:
Michael Trier&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Panelists:
Simon Willison, Russ Keith-Magee, Andrew Godwin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.djangocon.org"&gt;http://www.djangocon.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Michael Trier</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2008-09-06:djangocon-us-2008/djangocon-2008-panel-schema-evolution.html</guid><category>Django</category><category>panel</category><category>djangocon</category><category>djangocon2008</category></item><item><title>DjangoCon 2008: Pinax</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2008/djangocon-2008-pinax.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: James Tauber&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.djangocon.org"&gt;http://www.djangocon.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">James Tauber</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2008-09-06:djangocon-us-2008/djangocon-2008-pinax.html</guid><category>Django</category><category>djangocon</category><category>djangocon2008</category></item><item><title>DjangoCon 2008: Reusable Apps</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2008/djangocon-2008-reusable-apps.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: James Bennett&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.djangocon.org"&gt;http://www.djangocon.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">James Bennett</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2008-09-06:djangocon-us-2008/djangocon-2008-reusable-apps.html</guid><category>Django</category><category>djangocon</category><category>djangocon2008</category></item><item><title>DjangoCon 2008: ReviewBoard</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2008/djangocon-2008-reviewboard.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speakers: Christian Hammond &amp;amp; David Trowbridge&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.djangocon.org"&gt;http://www.djangocon.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Christian Hammond</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2008-09-06:djangocon-us-2008/djangocon-2008-reviewboard.html</guid><category>Django</category><category>djangocon</category><category>djangocon2008</category></item><item><title>DjangoCon 2008: Satchmo</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2008/djangocon-2008-satchmo.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speakers: Chris Moffitt and Bruce Kroeze&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.djangocon.org"&gt;http://www.djangocon.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Chris Moffitt</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2008-09-06:djangocon-us-2008/djangocon-2008-satchmo.html</guid><category>Django</category><category>djangocon</category><category>djangocon2008</category></item><item><title>DjangoCon 2008: TWID Live</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2008/djangocon-2008-twid-live.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speakers:
Michael Trier &amp;amp; Brian Rosner&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.djangocon.org"&gt;http://www.djangocon.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Michael Trier</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2008-09-06:djangocon-us-2008/djangocon-2008-twid-live.html</guid><category>Django</category><category>djangocon</category><category>djangocon2008</category></item><item><title>DjangoCon 2008: What's New in Newforms-Admin?</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-us-2008/djangocon-2008-whats-new-in-newforms-admin.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Brian Rosner&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.djangocon.org"&gt;http://www.djangocon.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Brian Rosner</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2008-09-06:djangocon-us-2008/djangocon-2008-whats-new-in-newforms-admin.html</guid><category>Django</category><category>djangocon</category><category>djangocon2008</category></item><item><title>Efficient Django - PyConES 2016</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-es-2016/efficient-django-pycones-2016.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;¿Es Django escalable? ¿Cómo sobrevivir a picos de tráfico? ¿Qué pasa cuando la base de datos crece demasiado? ¿Cómo encontrar los cuellos de botella?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Repasaremos los conceptos básicos, utilizaremos métricas para detectar cuellos de botella, y finalmente veremos trucos y consejos para mejorar la escalabilidad y el rendimiento de un proyecto Django.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Temas principales:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arquitectura escalable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rendimiento de la base de datos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Detección de cuellos de botella&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monitorización, profiling, debugging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optimizacion de queries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rendimiento del admin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Colas y workers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tests más rápidos.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presentación disponible en &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.slideshare.net/DZPM/efficient-django-64113328"&gt;http://www.slideshare.net/DZPM/efficient-django-64113328&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://2016.es.pycon.org/"&gt;http://2016.es.pycon.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">David Arcos</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-10-08:pycon-es-2016/efficient-django-pycones-2016.html</guid><category>Django</category></item><item><title>Creating Community Platforms with Django</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pydx-2016/creating-community-platforms-with-django.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyDX 2016 talk by Alison Acuña&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will explore different ways to create community platforms within Django including hand coding, Django Packages, and Pinax. We will examine:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pros and cons of using platforms/packages vs crafting original code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How different methods of community platform creation might impact the community develops on top of the platform.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Examples of each method and how to get started.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is intended for junior devs but all are welcome.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alison Acuña</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-12-30:pydx-2016/creating-community-platforms-with-django.html</guid><category>django</category></item><item><title>Frog and Toad Learn Django Security</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pydx-2016/frog-and-toad-learn-django-security.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyDX 2016 talk by Philip James&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come join us by the fire as we have Security Story Time with our friends, Frog and Toad. With them, you'll learn about all the things Django does to protect users and developers out of the box. We'll look at simplified code samples from the Django codebase to see what's happening under the hood, and cover how to make the Django security model even stronger in your application.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Philip James</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-12-30:pydx-2016/frog-and-toad-learn-django-security.html</guid><category>security</category><category>django</category></item><item><title>Advanced Permissioning</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2016/advanced-permissioning.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In many Django applications, permissioning (building rules for who has access to what) is pretty easy. Logged out users can see some stuff, logged in users can see more stuff, and superusers can see (and edit, and delete) all of the stuff! But when you want to handle more complex permissioning (like object-level permissions), it can get pretty ugly. This talk will help to de-uglify things for you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jack McCloy</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-07-16:pygotham-2016/advanced-permissioning.html</guid><category>Django</category></item><item><title>Django Best Practices</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-es-2013/django-best-practices.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Autor: David Arcos&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Track: Produban (Básico)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Django es un framework web Python de alto nivel que fomenta el desarrollo rápido y el diseño limpio y pragmático. La charla consistirá en varias propuestas de &amp;quot;best practices&amp;quot; respecto al desarrollo y despliegue de projectos Django, así como en el uso de las apps externas más importantes. Si bien la charla está orientada a desarrolladores Django, no es imprescindible tener experiencia previa.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">David Arcos</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-12-31:pycon-es-2013/django-best-practices.html</guid><category>django</category></item><item><title>Ticketea</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-es-2014/ticketea.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;En ticketea trabajamos con Python/Django en diversos proyectos que coexisten con un extenso stack tecnológico. Son muchas las lecciones aprendidas y las decisiones acertadas. Nuestro frontal, varias APIs, colas de tareas, business intelligence son algunos de estos proyectos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En esta charla, enseñaremos nuestra forma de entender Django y hacer escalar proyectos grandes manteniendo el orden y la calidad. Nuestras mejores prácticas y algunos hacks que hemos tenido que hacer para coexistir con éxito con PHP&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Miguel Alonso</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-04-06:pycon-es-2014/ticketea.html</guid><category>django</category></item><item><title>Having it All: Distributed services with Django, Boto, and SQS queues</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-es-2015/having-it-all-distributed-services-with-django-boto-and-sqs-queues.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;How do you let untrained people in your company run sensitive processes on different remote servers? Processes that must run asynchronously and sequentially while accessing different common resources? And how do you do it quickly and make it robust? I will show how we used Django, SQS and Boto to create a distributed and decoupled solution that let users invoke services asynchronously, which is secure, scalable and ensures that processes using common resources ran in sequence.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">J. V. Trigo</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-02-02:pycon-es-2015/having-it-all-distributed-services-with-django-boto-and-sqs-queues.html</guid><category>Track Básico</category><category>django</category><category>sqs</category><category>boto</category></item><item><title>Implantación de ElasticSearch: problemas y soluciones</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-es-2015/implantacion-de-elasticsearch-problemas-y-soluciones.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;En esta charla se presentará de manera resumida un caso real: el proceso de implantación de ElasticSearch en una aplicación de Django. Partiendo de la motivación de implementar un buscador, veremos los problemas encontrados por nuestro equipo (¡y sus soluciones!). A saber: instalación, definición de los documentos, modo de conexión, indexado, particionado y sincronía con nuestra base de datos.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">M. Sánchez</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-02-02:pycon-es-2015/implantacion-de-elasticsearch-problemas-y-soluciones.html</guid><category>Track Básico</category><category>elasticsearch</category><category>django</category></item><item><title>Single-Page Applications con Django y Backbone</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-es-2015/single-page-applications-con-django-y-backbone.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;En este taller llevaremos a cabo un caso práctico. La construcción de una Single-Page Application usando Backbone como herramienta front-end. Ahora que cada día aparece una docena de frameworks de JavaScript, suena sensato buscar algo de estabilidad en un framework de trayectoria ya constatada, como es Backbone. Por otra parte, tener un framework como Django en el back-end proporciona robustez, facilidad de uso y muchísima extensibilidad -gracias al increíble ecosistema pythónico-.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Miguel Sánchez Rodríguez</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-02-02:pycon-es-2015/single-page-applications-con-django-y-backbone.html</guid><category>workshop</category><category>single-page application</category><category>django</category><category>backbone</category></item><item><title>Comparing Wagtail, Django CMS and Mezzanine</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2016/comparing-wagtail-django-cms-and-mezzanine.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Adam Brenecki
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2016.pycon-au.org/schedule/102/view_talk"&gt;https://2016.pycon-au.org/schedule/102/view_talk&lt;/a&gt;
Django CMS, Mezzanine and Wagtail are the three most popular Django-based content management systems; all three have kept (or, in Wagtail's case, gained) their popularity because they are so different to each other. In many ways, from their fundamental data models right through to how they approach their content editing UIs, each one has a very different take on how a CMS should work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will explore the different approaches, strengths and weaknesses of each CMS, and what they mean for you as a developer and for your content editors.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Adam Brenecki</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-15:pycon-au-2016/comparing-wagtail-django-cms-and-mezzanine.html</guid><category>django</category><category>django cms</category><category>mezzanine</category><category>wagtail</category></item><item><title>Digitising 100 years of parliamentary data - Django as a framework for government data management</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2016/digitising-100-years-of-parliamentary-data-django-as-a-framework-for-government-data-management.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Samuel Spencer
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2016.pycon-au.org/schedule/135/view_talk"&gt;https://2016.pycon-au.org/schedule/135/view_talk&lt;/a&gt;
Historical information on Australian Parliaments has been available in the Parliamentary Library's flagship publication the Parliamentary Handbook - an extensive almanac with biographies, tables and records dating back to Australia's federation. This data is used as a way to track key social issues, such as length of service, gender representation in parliament and historical election information in an authoritative format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To improve access to this information the library began development of a mobile app which evolved into a complete Django-based data management system for managing parliamentary biographies and service histories based on Popolo, a civic data framework for the management and dissemination of parliamentary information. Along with interactive biographies and records of ministries and parties, the system for the first time allows users to build custom tables from complex queries that are dynamically updated as new information is made available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coupled with this is the development of a biographical data management system that will ensure that records of new parliamentarians and future changes to existing parliamentarians are captured in a single system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this presentation, we cover the challenges and successes in digitising over 100 years parliamentary data, including migration, data cleansing and data trust issues. We also provide a technical breakdown of the chosen framework and infrastructure, and issues during development especially when dealing with imprecise or incomplete historical records. Lastly, we cover the Django apps for data modelling and querying built for this project that have already been released as open-source.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Samuel Spencer</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-15:pycon-au-2016/digitising-100-years-of-parliamentary-data-django-as-a-framework-for-government-data-management.html</guid><category>django</category></item><item><title>Django - Customise your SQL</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2016/django-customise-your-sql.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Josh Smeaton
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2016.pycon-au.org/schedule/86/view_talk"&gt;https://2016.pycon-au.org/schedule/86/view_talk&lt;/a&gt;
Learn about the different methods of altering the SQL that the Django ORM generates. Write complex reporting queries, perform calculations within the database, or drop down to writing the entire query in pure SQL. Take advantage of your specific database features.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Josh Smeaton</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-15:pycon-au-2016/django-customise-your-sql.html</guid><category>django</category></item><item><title>Django &amp; Drupal: A tale of two cities.</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2016/django-drupal-a-tale-of-two-cities.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Donna Benjamin
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2016.pycon-au.org/schedule/201/view_talk"&gt;https://2016.pycon-au.org/schedule/201/view_talk&lt;/a&gt;
Drupal and Django have much in common. They’re both open source tools for building the web. They’re also marked by some fundamental differences. However, both are so much more than that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Every human creature is constituted to be that profound secret and mystery to every other. A solemn consideration, when I enter a great city by night, that every one of those darkly clustered houses encloses its own secret; that every room in every one of them encloses its own secret!&amp;quot; - Charles Dickens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s explore the darkly clustered houses of these two different communities of open source people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What common challenges do we face?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What different approaches do we take?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What can we learn from each other?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally, what could we do together?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Donna Benjamin</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-15:pycon-au-2016/django-drupal-a-tale-of-two-cities.html</guid><category>django</category><category>drupal</category></item><item><title>DjangoConf Lightning Talks and Closing</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2016/djangoconf-lightning-talks-and-closing.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Unknown</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-15:pycon-au-2016/djangoconf-lightning-talks-and-closing.html</guid><category>django</category><category>lightning talks</category></item><item><title>Integrating 2 factor authentication into your project</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2016/integrating-2-factor-authentication-into-your-project.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Markus Holtermann
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2016.pycon-au.org/schedule/31/view_talk"&gt;https://2016.pycon-au.org/schedule/31/view_talk&lt;/a&gt;
Most websites these days require some kind of authentication. User name + password is the most common one. OAuth with Facebook / Github / Google / Twitter is also common. But sometimes you can't rely on 3rd party services and user name + password is not enough. In those cases 2 Factor Authentication is a nice, additional security layer. Use e.g. a phone to ensure a more secure authentication.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Markus Holtermann</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-15:pycon-au-2016/integrating-2-factor-authentication-into-your-project.html</guid><category>django</category></item><item><title>Behind Closed Doors: Managing Passwords in a Dangerous World</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2016/pycon-au-2016-behind-closed-doors-managing-passwords-in-a-dangerous-world.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Noah Kantrowitz
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2016.pycon-au.org/schedule/61/view_talk"&gt;https://2016.pycon-au.org/schedule/61/view_talk&lt;/a&gt;
Secrets come in many forms, passwords, keys, tokens. All crucial for the operation of an application, but each dangerous in its own way. In the past, many of us have pasted those secrets in to a text file and moved on, but in a world of config automation and ephemeral microservices these patterns are leaving our data at greater risk than ever before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New tools, products, and libraries are being released all the time to try to cope with this massive rise in threats, both new and old-but-ignored. This talk will cover the major types of secrets in a normal web application, how to model their security properties, what tools are best for each situation, and how to use them with major web frameworks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Noah Kantrowitz</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-15:pycon-au-2016/pycon-au-2016-behind-closed-doors-managing-passwords-in-a-dangerous-world.html</guid><category>django</category></item><item><title>Reinventing Django for the Real-Time Web</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2016/reinventing-django-for-the-real-time-web.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Andrew Godwin
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2016.pycon-au.org/schedule/28/view_talk"&gt;https://2016.pycon-au.org/schedule/28/view_talk&lt;/a&gt;
Django's new Channels feature takes Django beyond the world of HTTP's request-response protocol and into the modern Web protocol world of WebSockets and real-time communication - but it also does a lot more. Learn how Django can now respond to WebSockets, emails or instant messages as easily as HTTP, and we re-architected Django to support all these changes while keeping a clean API and backwards compatibility, and the implications it has for the wider Python ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Andrew Godwin</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-15:pycon-au-2016/reinventing-django-for-the-real-time-web.html</guid><category>django</category></item><item><title>Search-First Writing for Developers</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2016/search-first-writing-for-developers.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Heidi Waterhouse
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2016.pycon-au.org/schedule/47/view_talk"&gt;https://2016.pycon-au.org/schedule/47/view_talk&lt;/a&gt;
If people can't use your software, you have already failed as a developer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk digs in to how optimizing for search and using the existing technical assistance forums can put your product ahead of the pack. Technical writing, in all its variations, is a type of interface with your product. It incorporates everything from an error message to an implementation guide. How can you as a developer make deploying, using, and promoting your product as painless as possible? Make it searchable. Make finding the answer to a problem so trivially easy that your user barely even remembers they had a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No one wants to be using software. They want to be data mining or manipulating beautiful photos or targeting advertising. Making them think about the software diverts them from what they want to be accomplishing. Use these documentation techniques to get them in and out and on their way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(my secret is: I'm always angry when I have to read help)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Heidi Waterhouse</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-15:pycon-au-2016/search-first-writing-for-developers.html</guid><category>django</category></item><item><title>Best practices for scaling Django</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2016/best-practices-for-scaling-django.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can find more about this talk on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2016.djangocon.eu/speakers/16"&gt;djangocon.eu&lt;/a&gt;. This video is hosted by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://opbeat.com/community/posts/best-practices-for-scaling-django-by-anton-pirker/"&gt;opbeat.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Anton Pirker</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-04-01:djangocon-europe-2016/best-practices-for-scaling-django.html</guid><category>django</category></item><item><title>Beyond Web 2.0 - Django and Python in the modern web ecosystem</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2016/beyond-web-20-django-and-python-in-the-modern-web-ecosystem.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can find more about this talk on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2016.djangocon.eu/speakers/5"&gt;djangocon.eu&lt;/a&gt;. This video is hosted by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://opbeat.com/community/posts/beyond-web-2-0-django-and-python-in-the-modern-web-ecosystem-by-russell-keith-magee/"&gt;opbeat.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Dr. Russell Keith-Magee</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-04-01:djangocon-europe-2016/beyond-web-20-django-and-python-in-the-modern-web-ecosystem.html</guid><category>django</category></item><item><title>Lightning talks, day 3</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2016/djangocon-eu-2016-lightning-talks-day-3.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This video is hosted by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://opbeat.com/community/posts/lightning-talks-day-3/"&gt;opbeat.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Various speakers</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-04-01:djangocon-europe-2016/djangocon-eu-2016-lightning-talks-day-3.html</guid><category>lightning talks</category><category>django</category></item><item><title>Don't be afraid of writing migrations</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2016/dont-be-afraid-of-writing-migrations.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can find more about this talk on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2016.djangocon.eu/speakers/4"&gt;djangocon.eu&lt;/a&gt;. This video is hosted by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://opbeat.com/community/posts/dont-be-afraid-of-writing-migrations-by-markus-holtermann/"&gt;opbeat.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Markus Holtermann</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-04-01:djangocon-europe-2016/dont-be-afraid-of-writing-migrations.html</guid><category>django</category></item><item><title>From Intern to Professional Developer: Advice on a Mid-Career Pivot</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2016/from-intern-to-professional-developer-advice-on-a-mid-career-pivot.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can find more about this talk on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2016.djangocon.eu/speakers/8"&gt;djangocon.eu&lt;/a&gt;. This video is hosted by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://opbeat.com/community/posts/from-intern-to-professional-developer-advice-on-a-mid-career-pivot-by-rebecca-conley/"&gt;opbeat.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Rebecca Conley</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-04-01:djangocon-europe-2016/from-intern-to-professional-developer-advice-on-a-mid-career-pivot.html</guid><category>django</category></item><item><title>Let's Talk Geo: Adding the 'Where' to Your Django Project</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2016/lets-talk-geo-adding-the-where-to-your-django-project.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can find more about this talk on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2016.djangocon.eu/speakers/19"&gt;djangocon.eu&lt;/a&gt;. This video is hosted by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://opbeat.com/community/posts/lets-talk-geo-adding-the-where-to-your-django-project-by-corryn-smith/"&gt;opbeat.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Corryn Smith</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-04-01:djangocon-europe-2016/lets-talk-geo-adding-the-where-to-your-django-project.html</guid><category>django</category></item><item><title>Safe-Ish by Default: The Django Security Model and How to Make it Better</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2016/safe-ish-by-default-the-django-security-model-and-how-to-make-it-better.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can find more about this talk on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2016.djangocon.eu/speakers/23"&gt;djangocon.eu&lt;/a&gt;. This video is hosted by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://opbeat.com/community/posts/safe-ish-by-default-the-django-security-model-and-how-to-make-it-better-by-philip-james/"&gt;opbeat.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Philip James</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-04-01:djangocon-europe-2016/safe-ish-by-default-the-django-security-model-and-how-to-make-it-better.html</guid><category>django</category></item><item><title>Using Django with service workers</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2016/using-django-with-service-workers.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can find more about this talk on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2016.djangocon.eu/speakers/10"&gt;djangocon.eu&lt;/a&gt;. This video is hosted by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://opbeat.com/community/posts/using-django-with-service-workers-by-adrian-holovaty/"&gt;opbeat.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Adrian Holovaty</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-04-01:djangocon-europe-2016/using-django-with-service-workers.html</guid><category>django</category></item><item><title>A Brief History of Channels</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2016/a-brief-history-of-channels.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can find more about this talk on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2016.djangocon.eu/speakers/7"&gt;djangocon.eu&lt;/a&gt;. This video is hosted by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://opbeat.com/community/posts/a-brief-history-of-channels-by-andrew-godwin/"&gt;opbeat.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Andrew Godwin</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-03-31:djangocon-europe-2016/a-brief-history-of-channels.html</guid><category>django</category></item><item><title>Building A Non-Relational Backend For The ORM</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2016/building-a-non-relational-backend-for-the-orm.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can find more about this talk on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2016.djangocon.eu/speakers/3"&gt;djangocon.eu&lt;/a&gt;. This video is hosted by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://opbeat.com/community/posts/building-a-non-relational-backend-for-the-orm-by-adam-alton/"&gt;opbeat.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Adam Alton</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-03-31:djangocon-europe-2016/building-a-non-relational-backend-for-the-orm.html</guid><category>django</category></item><item><title>Django Microservices Made Easy</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2016/django-microservices-made-easy.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can find more about this talk on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2016.djangocon.eu/speakers/20"&gt;djangocon.eu&lt;/a&gt;. This video is hosted by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://opbeat.com/community/posts/django-microservices-made-easy-by-paul-hallett/"&gt;opbeat.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Paul Hallett</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-03-31:djangocon-europe-2016/django-microservices-made-easy.html</guid><category>django</category></item><item><title>Lightning talks, day 2</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2016/djangocon-eu-2016-lightning-talks-day-2.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This video is hosted by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://opbeat.com/community/posts/lightning-talks-day-2/"&gt;opbeat.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Various speakers</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-03-31:djangocon-europe-2016/djangocon-eu-2016-lightning-talks-day-2.html</guid><category>lightning talks</category><category>django</category></item><item><title>Hermione Granger and the Wizard Information System</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2016/hermione-granger-and-the-wizard-information-system.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can find more about this talk on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2016.djangocon.eu/speakers/6"&gt;djangocon.eu&lt;/a&gt;. This video is hosted by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://opbeat.com/community/posts/hermione-granger-and-the-wizard-information-system-by-lacey-williams-henschel/"&gt;opbeat.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Lacey Williams Henschel</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-03-31:djangocon-europe-2016/hermione-granger-and-the-wizard-information-system.html</guid><category>django</category></item><item><title>HTTP/2: why upgrading the web?</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2016/http2-why-upgrading-the-web.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can find more about this talk on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2016.djangocon.eu/speakers/2"&gt;djangocon.eu&lt;/a&gt;. This video is hosted by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://opbeat.com/community/posts/http2-why-upgrading-the-web-by-quentin-adam/"&gt;opbeat.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Quentin Adam</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-03-31:djangocon-europe-2016/http2-why-upgrading-the-web.html</guid><category>django</category></item><item><title>Introducing Django To The Foreign World</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2016/introducing-django-to-the-foreign-world.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can find more about this talk on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2016.djangocon.eu/speakers/21"&gt;djangocon.eu&lt;/a&gt;. This video is hosted by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://opbeat.com/community/posts/introducing-django-to-the-foreign-world-by-bashar-al-abdulhadi/"&gt;opbeat.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Bashar Al-Abdulhadi</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-03-31:djangocon-europe-2016/introducing-django-to-the-foreign-world.html</guid><category>django</category></item><item><title>IoT with Django: From hackathon to production</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2016/iot-with-django-from-hackathon-to-production.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can find more about this talk on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2016.djangocon.eu/speakers/9"&gt;djangocon.eu&lt;/a&gt;. This video is hosted by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://opbeat.com/community/posts/iot-with-django-from-hackathon-to-production-by-anna-schneider/"&gt;opbeat.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Anna Schneider</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-03-31:djangocon-europe-2016/iot-with-django-from-hackathon-to-production.html</guid><category>django</category></item><item><title>Keynote: The Art of Programming</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2016/keynote-the-art-of-programming.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can find more about this talk on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2016.djangocon.eu/speakers/22"&gt;djangocon.eu&lt;/a&gt;. This video is hosted by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://opbeat.com/community/posts/keynote-the-art-of-programming-by-erika-heidi/"&gt;opbeat.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Erika Heidi</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-03-31:djangocon-europe-2016/keynote-the-art-of-programming.html</guid><category>django</category></item><item><title>The Power ⚡️ and Responsibility 😓 of Unicode Adoption ✨</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2016/the-power-and-responsibility-of-unicode-adoption.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can find more about this talk on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2016.djangocon.eu/speakers/11"&gt;djangocon.eu&lt;/a&gt;. This video is hosted by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://opbeat.com/community/posts/the-power-and-responsibility-of-unicode-adoption-by-katie-mclaughlin/"&gt;opbeat.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Katie McLaughlin</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-03-31:djangocon-europe-2016/the-power-and-responsibility-of-unicode-adoption.html</guid><category>django</category></item><item><title>Django and ReactJS: The good, the bad and the ugly</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2016/django-and-reactjs-the-good-the-bad-and-the-ugly.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can find more about this talk on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2016.djangocon.eu/speakers/12"&gt;djangocon.eu&lt;/a&gt;. This video is hosted by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://opbeat.com/community/posts/django-and-reactjs-the-good-the-bad-and-the-ugly-by-tomas-ehrlich/"&gt;opbeat.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tomáš Ehrlich</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-03-30:djangocon-europe-2016/django-and-reactjs-the-good-the-bad-and-the-ugly.html</guid><category>django</category></item><item><title>Lightning talks, day 1</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2016/djangocon-eu-2016-lightning-talks-day-1.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This video is hosted by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://opbeat.com/community/posts/lightning-talks-day-1/"&gt;opbeat.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Various speakers</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-03-30:djangocon-europe-2016/djangocon-eu-2016-lightning-talks-day-1.html</guid><category>lightning talks</category><category>django</category></item><item><title>Going with the flow with Django Admin</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2016/going-with-the-flow-with-django-admin.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can find more about this talk on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2016.djangocon.eu/speakers/14"&gt;djangocon.eu&lt;/a&gt;. This video is hosted by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://opbeat.com/community/posts/going-with-the-flow-with-django-admin-by-maria-lowas-rzechonek/"&gt;opbeat.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Maria Lowas-Rzechonek</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-03-30:djangocon-europe-2016/going-with-the-flow-with-django-admin.html</guid><category>django</category></item><item><title>Healthy Minds in a Healthy Community</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2016/healthy-minds-in-a-healthy-community.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can find more about this talk on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2016.djangocon.eu/speakers/13"&gt;djangocon.eu&lt;/a&gt;. This video is hosted by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://opbeat.com/community/posts/healthy-minds-in-a-healthy-community-by-erik-romijn-and-mikey-ariel/"&gt;opbeat.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Erik Romijn</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-03-30:djangocon-europe-2016/healthy-minds-in-a-healthy-community.html</guid><category>django</category></item><item><title>How to Upgrade to the Newest and Shiniest Django</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2016/how-to-upgrade-to-the-newest-and-shiniest-django.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can find more about this talk on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2016.djangocon.eu/speakers/24"&gt;djangocon.eu&lt;/a&gt;. This video is hosted by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://opbeat.com/community/posts/how-to-upgrade-to-the-newest-and-shiniest-django-by-susan-tan/"&gt;opbeat.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Susan Tan</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-03-30:djangocon-europe-2016/how-to-upgrade-to-the-newest-and-shiniest-django.html</guid><category>django</category></item><item><title>Learning Django, Learning French</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2016/learning-django-learning-french.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can find more about this talk on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2016.djangocon.eu/speakers/15"&gt;djangocon.eu&lt;/a&gt;. This video is hosted by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://opbeat.com/community/posts/learning-django-learning-french-by-nicole-harris/"&gt;opbeat.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nicole Harris</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-03-30:djangocon-europe-2016/learning-django-learning-french.html</guid><category>django</category></item><item><title>Rub-a-Dub Rubber Duck: Don’t Be Afraid to Debug!</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2016/rub-a-dub-rubber-duck-dont-be-afraid-to-debug.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can find more about this talk on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2016.djangocon.eu/speakers/1"&gt;djangocon.eu&lt;/a&gt;. This video is hosted by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://opbeat.com/community/posts/rub-a-dub-rubber-duck-dont-be-afraid-to-debug-by-anna-ossowski/"&gt;opbeat.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Anna Ossowski</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-03-30:djangocon-europe-2016/rub-a-dub-rubber-duck-dont-be-afraid-to-debug.html</guid><category>django</category></item><item><title>The Front-End Revolution</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2016/the-front-end-revolution.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can find more about this talk on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2016.djangocon.eu/speakers/25"&gt;djangocon.eu&lt;/a&gt;. This video is hosted by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://opbeat.com/community/posts/the-front-end-revolution-by-claudina-sarahe/"&gt;opbeat.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Claudina Sarahe</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-03-30:djangocon-europe-2016/the-front-end-revolution.html</guid><category>django</category></item><item><title>To mock, or not to mock, that is the question</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-europe-2016/to-mock-or-not-to-mock-that-is-the-question.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can find more about this talk on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2016.djangocon.eu/speakers/18"&gt;djangocon.eu&lt;/a&gt;. This video is hosted by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://opbeat.com/community/posts/to-mock-or-not-to-mock-that-is-the-question-by-ana-balica/"&gt;opbeat.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ana Balica</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-03-30:djangocon-europe-2016/to-mock-or-not-to-mock-that-is-the-question.html</guid><category>django</category></item><item><title>Custom user models in Django</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycaribbean-2016/custom-user-models-in-django.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alexander Bliskovsky</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-02-21:pycaribbean-2016/custom-user-models-in-django.html</guid><category>django</category></item><item><title>Build a one page with Django and Angular</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycaribbean-2016/pycaribbean-2016-build-a-one-page-with-django-and-angular-by-jose-a-hernadez-rosales.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk we'll be learning the ins and outs of how to develop a Single Page Application using Angular and Django.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;José A. Hernández Rosale&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">José A. Hernádez Rosales</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-02-20:pycaribbean-2016/pycaribbean-2016-build-a-one-page-with-django-and-angular-by-jose-a-hernadez-rosales.html</guid><category>Django</category><category>Angular</category></item></channel></rss>