<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_devops.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>How to Write Deployment-friendly Applications</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2018/how-to-write-deployment-friendly-applications.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Hynek Schlawack</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-12:pycon-us-2018/how-to-write-deployment-friendly-applications.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The DevOps movement gave us many ways to put Python applications into production.  But should your &lt;em&gt;application&lt;/em&gt; care?  Should it need to know whether it’s running on your notebook, on a server, in a Docker container, or in some cloud platform as a service?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It should not, because environment-agnostic applications are easier to &lt;strong&gt;test&lt;/strong&gt;, easier to &lt;strong&gt;deploy&lt;/strong&gt;, easier to &lt;strong&gt;handle&lt;/strong&gt;, and easier to &lt;strong&gt;scale&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But how can you &lt;em&gt;practically&lt;/em&gt; structure and configure your applications to make them indifferent to the environment they run in?  How do secrets fit into the picture?  And where do you put that log file?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of this talk you’ll know the tools and techniques that enable you to write such Python applications and you’ll be ready for the next big change.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="devops"></category></entry><entry><title>Devops com Python</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/caipyra-2016/devops-com-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-06-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-06-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Humberto Diógenes</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-06-26:caipyra-2016/devops-com-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Palestra do Humberto Diógenes no Caipyra 2016:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Devops com Python&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="devops"></category></entry><entry><title>Containerize all the things</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/caipyra-2016/containerize-all-the-things.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-06-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-06-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Andrews Medina</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-06-25:caipyra-2016/containerize-all-the-things.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Palestra do Andrews Medina no Caipyra 2016:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Containerize all the things&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://talks.godoc.org/github.com/andrewsmedina/containerize-all-the-things/sample.slide#1"&gt;http://talks.godoc.org/github.com/andrewsmedina/containerize-all-the-things/sample.slide#1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="docker"></category><category term="devops"></category></entry><entry><title>An Admin's Cornucopia - Python Is More Than Just A Better Bash</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2017/an-admins-cornucopia-python-is-more-than-just-a-better-bash.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Christian Theune</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-25:pycon-de-2017/an-admins-cornucopia-python-is-more-than-just-a-better-bash.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Christian Theune&lt;/strong&gt; (&amp;#64;theuni)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python's versatility is known to admins - in this talk I'd like to show how it fits for many small and big challenges I meet regularly: from tiny scripts to large systems. Also, I'll show how using the languages' advanced and/or newer features makes scripts more compact and robust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DRAFT Unfortunately I got sick just a few days before the CFP date, so hopefully you can live with a draft description for now. I'll be happy to update this during or after the review as needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd like to give a hands-on approach for how to use Python in a mixed environment where you may be writing very small standalone scripts, small integration programs and/or larger systems. As an admin bash is always a very close friend and one quickly uses it and then ends up with large scripts that should never have seen the day of light. Also, admins nowadays might be writing larger software bases that are actual software projects and the lines between &amp;quot;ops&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;devs&amp;quot; are - on purpose - more and more blurry. However, there are some differences in &amp;quot;application development&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;system development&amp;quot;. Those are more of a mindset issue, however, and Python as a technology fits in both situations quite well and allows one to transition between those modes rather seamlessly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll be reviewing specific pieces of code from our infrastructure, ranging from smaller scripts to subsystems to a full-born Pyramid application that we use for inventory management. All of those will use different versions of Python, different libraries and different approaches how to solve certain problems. I will likely show how not to do things as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recorded at&lt;/strong&gt; PyCon.DE 2017 Karlsruhe: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://de.pycon.org/"&gt;https://de.pycon.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video editing&lt;/strong&gt;: Sebastian Neubauer &amp;amp; Andrei Dan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tools&lt;/strong&gt;: Blender, Avidemux &amp;amp; Sonic Pi&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="python"></category><category term="devops"></category></entry><entry><title>Automated testing with 400TB memory</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2017/automated-testing-with-400tb-memory.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Christoph Heer</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-25:pycon-de-2017/automated-testing-with-400tb-memory.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Christoph Heer&lt;/strong&gt; (&amp;#64;ChristophHeer)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m an Infrastructure Engineer in the team behind SAP’s huge test infrastructure for SAP HANA. In my spare time, I develop web applications with Django or playing around with new programming languages like Rust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SAP operates a dedicated test infrastructure with more than 400TB main memory for its in-memory database SAP HANA. All custom implementations like improved scheduling, caching of artifacts and monitoring were implemented in our favorite programming language Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SAP operates a large test infrastructure to test its in-memory database SAP HANA. In 2010, we started with a single Jenkins master with ten nodes. But to keep our testing time acceptable for the growing number of developers we had to scale up, which led to multiple different scaling challenges. The current test infrastructure is powered by more than thousand physical servers and provides different services like continuous integration, code coverage and code linting for a huge C++ project. These services are essential for developing and shipping new SAP HANA versions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk provides insights into how we scaled and improved our test infrastructure. All custom implementations like improved scheduling, expressive test configuration and caching of artifacts were implemented in our favorite programming language Python. With the flexibility and power of Python it has been easier to extend, optimize and adapt the infrastructure for new requirements like different CPU architectures and newer operating system versions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recorded at&lt;/strong&gt; PyCon.DE 2017 Karlsruhe: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://de.pycon.org/"&gt;https://de.pycon.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video editing&lt;/strong&gt;: Sebastian Neubauer &amp;amp; Andrei Dan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tools&lt;/strong&gt;: Blender, Avidemux &amp;amp; Sonic Pi&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="python"></category><category term="use-case"></category><category term="devops"></category><category term="business"></category></entry><entry><title>Building your own SDN with Debian Linux, Salt Stack and Python</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2017/building-your-own-sdn-with-debian-linux-salt-stack-and-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Maximilian Wilhelm</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-25:pycon-de-2017/building-your-own-sdn-with-debian-linux-salt-stack-and-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maximilian Wilhelm&lt;/strong&gt; (&amp;#64;BarbarossaTM)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By day Maximilian Wilhelm is working as a Senior Infrastructure Architect in the central computing department of the University of Paderborn, by night he's hacking on the infrastructure of the Freifunk Hochstift network and some Open Source projects. Since the early 2000s he has a heart for Linux and Open Source, developed a weaknes for networking, IPv6 and routing a long while a go and has beed a speaker and tutor at the #Routingdays. Lately he got his hands dirty with ifupdown2, VXLAN, Linux VRFs, infrastructure automation with Salt Stack and &amp;quot;kommunistischen Frickelnetzen&amp;quot; and is afraid of SDNs ever since. In his spare time he likes playing piano and the organ, taking pictures of natures and cute animals, and trying to stay on the board while Windsurfing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk you will get an overview about some awesome features of comtemporary Linux networking, how to easily integrate them with some cool open source tools, and glueing all this together with Salt Stack and some Python to get your very own SDN controller for a service-provider style network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Topics like Infrastructure Automation / Orchestration, Cloud, and Software Defined Networks are on everyones tongue and nearly all network vendors who think highly of themselves provide products and maybe even solutions in this sphere of buzzwords.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within the last years there has been a paradigm shift towards host and segment routing – think »IP Fabric« – as well as a focus on open protocols and standards like OSPF, IS-IS, BGP &amp;amp; MPLS not only in the data center. This even brought us some new standards like VXLAN and a bunch of open source based “open networking” platforms. Now we aren't always locked to the operating systems of a networking vendor but can choose the control plane software from a variety of Linux based solutions which can be managed and orchestrated by lots of different means.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the Linux basis and the Open Source spirit of some vendors, some features (VRFs, MPLS forwarding plane, …) today are part of the upstream Linux kernel and available for everyone! Most notable are the contributions of the Debian Linux based platform from Cumulus Networks, which include the VRF support for Linux, some MPLS patches for FRR and ifupdown2 (which is written in Python :-)).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Putting a bunch of these technologies and ideas together will open up a lot of powerful options for building low budget yet mighty networks. This talk will lay out how to build a SDN based service provide like infrastructure with the help of Salt Stack, some 1000 lines of Python and a bunch of affordable hardware where overlay networks and anycast aren't things to be scared of. The Freifunk Hochstift network and server infrastructure will be used as an example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The target audience mainly consists of (Linux-) system and network engineers / architects, who already have some experience with the other world. A positive attitude towards automation and magic is a plus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recorded at&lt;/strong&gt; PyCon.DE 2017 Karlsruhe: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://de.pycon.org/"&gt;https://de.pycon.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video editing&lt;/strong&gt;: Sebastian Neubauer &amp;amp; Andrei Dan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tools&lt;/strong&gt;: Blender, Avidemux &amp;amp; Sonic Pi&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="sdn"></category><category term="saltstack"></category><category term="linux"></category><category term="debian"></category><category term="networking"></category><category term="devops"></category><category term="use-case"></category><category term="netops"></category><category term="netdevops"></category></entry><entry><title>From 0 to Continuous Delivery in 30 minutes.</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2017/from-0-to-continuous-delivery-in-30-minutes.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>David Wölfe</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-25:pycon-de-2017/from-0-to-continuous-delivery-in-30-minutes.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An introduction and hands on example how to start Continuous Delivery for python (or whatever) projects with conda and gitlab, which are open source, free to use, and if you wish even available as a cloud service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, you wrote this neat software, which uses one or two cool 3rd party packages and now you have to get it running on your test or prod servers. Now you could check out your code and install the dependencies manually but that seems like a lot of wasted time, right? Shouldn't there be a more convenient way of doing this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes! And it's easier than you think! In this talk you'll learn how to build a Continuous Delivery pipeline for your python (or whatever) projects in 30 Minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the beginning you'll get a quick introduction into the topic and the used tools, which are open source and free to use. For those who know a little about the subject: We will use conda (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://conda.io"&gt;https://conda.io&lt;/a&gt;) to build the software package and for the dependency handling. GitLab.com will process the actual pipeline for us and Anaconda.com serves us with a package distribution channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that it's &amp;quot;hands on&amp;quot; time. We will go step by step trough the process. Starting with the creation of a little dummy program. Then extending the dummy in such manner that it can be build into a package. Afterwards we will create the pipeline and finally do a demo deploy. And if the gods of conference internet are merciful, you see all this as a live demonstration.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="hands on"></category><category term="continuous delivery"></category><category term="devops"></category><category term="python"></category><category term="gitlab"></category><category term="conda"></category></entry><entry><title>Keeping the grip on decoupled code using CLIs</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2017/keeping-the-grip-on-decoupled-code-using-clis.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Anne Matthies</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-25:pycon-de-2017/keeping-the-grip-on-decoupled-code-using-clis.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anne Matthies&lt;/strong&gt; (&amp;#64;babeltron)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anne Matthies has been coding data stuff professionally since 1996. She switched to Python 2 in 2000, to Python 3 in 2015. Currently, she’s working at Babbel, Berlin, responsible for building and operating the data platform – and developing the next generation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So you’ve decoupled your code monolith into all those micro chunks. When someone asks &amp;quot;How can I…&amp;quot; you want to answer: &amp;quot;That’s easy! We’ve built that.&amp;quot; Actually, you’ve built all parts needed for that. Who plugs them together? And how?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keeping the grip on decoupled code using CLIs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So you’ve decoupled your monolith spaghetti code into micro chunks. You’ve switched to infrastructure as code, and you’re confident that it scales horizontally. Your data pipelines are pretty resilient, your CI pipeline runs tests on every single git push.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then, you get a new team member. Or your CTO wants to plot data of his brandnew sandbox project that isn’t integrated into your pipelines. Or someone just asks &amp;quot;How can I…&amp;quot; and you want to answer: &amp;quot;That’s easy! We’ve built that… – Well, actually, we’ve built all parts needed for that.&amp;quot; Who plugs them together? And how?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my talk, I’d like to show how lightweight CLIs can be Ariadne Threads through the labyrinth of micro components. How at Babbel we use conda, setuptools entrypoints and simple CLI scripts to keep the grip on our data platform code chunks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recorded at&lt;/strong&gt; PyCon.DE 2017 Karlsruhe: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://de.pycon.org/"&gt;https://de.pycon.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video editing&lt;/strong&gt;: Sebastian Neubauer &amp;amp; Andrei Dan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tools&lt;/strong&gt;: Blender, Avidemux &amp;amp; Sonic Pi&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="pydata"></category><category term="devops"></category><category term="cli"></category><category term="python"></category></entry><entry><title>No Compromise: Use Ansible properly or stick to your scripts</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2017/no-compromise-use-ansible-properly-or-stick-to-your-scripts.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Björn Meier</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-25:pycon-de-2017/no-compromise-use-ansible-properly-or-stick-to-your-scripts.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bjoern Meier&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bjoern is a software engineer at Blue Yonder GmbH since 2016 after graduating in Computer Science. More correctly you could say he is a DevOps engineer at Blue Yonder where he is developing and operating - among other things - the services for the external data interfaces, preprocessing and data storage to enable the data scientists to run their prediction models. He loves the versatility and ecosystem of python to write e.g. production web apps, data analysis tools or operational scripts. If there was more free time he would like to spent it to dive deeper into functional programming languages like elixir to have a different view on things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What you do in Ansible should be clean an simple. What we did was not. So I will show what we did wrong but also what we have changed or still have to, to make our life easier again. But I will also show how we progressively utilize Ansible to deploy our Data Science infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ansible should help you to orchestrate your systems, automate the deployments and set up well defined infrastructures. But if you want to make something work quickly in Ansible the chances are high that you fall back to shell/command tasks, the mother of all evil. Those tasks usually prevent you from running dry runs where you would see the upcoming changes and you prevent Ansible to shine. So, we went blindly into every deployment and hoped the best. But we wanted to see what would change, we wanted to make ansible --check work again and therefore in this talk I will show you what we did wrong and what we changed to get there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More precisely, I will show what you can do to replace the nasty shell tasks with proper modules, plugins and filters, how they are developed, tested and included in your project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recorded at&lt;/strong&gt; PyCon.DE 2017 Karlsruhe: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://de.pycon.org/"&gt;https://de.pycon.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video editing&lt;/strong&gt;: Sebastian Neubauer &amp;amp; Andrei Dan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tools&lt;/strong&gt;: Blender, Avidemux &amp;amp; Sonic Pi&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="infrasturcture"></category><category term="business"></category><category term="devops"></category><category term="ansible"></category></entry><entry><title>Python with Apache OpenWhisk</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2017/python-with-apache-openwhisk.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ansgar Schmidt</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-25:pycon-de-2017/python-with-apache-openwhisk.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ansgar Schmidt&lt;/strong&gt; (&amp;#64;ansi)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a full time nerd. Really thrilled by technology and love to make and hack. From PCB design, soldering, embedded development to server- backend hacking. Beside way to many small projects I work on a mobile robot based on ROS and try to add human interaction to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OpenWhisk is an opensource implementation of a so called serverless computing platform. At a live presentation I will show how to write an serverless application and how to deal with libraries and events. OpenWhisk is an open source alternative to AWS lambda or MS functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi, I am a developer advocate working for IBM. Meaning I am a technician and geek not a salesman. In my talk I will give a live demo on how to use the open source implementation of a serverless compute platform called OpenWhisk and help python developers on how to use it and write serverless applications.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="devops"></category><category term="use-case"></category><category term="python"></category><category term="web"></category><category term="business"></category></entry><entry><title>Sport analysis with Python</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2017/sport-analysis-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Thuy Le</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-10-25:pycon-de-2017/sport-analysis-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give an example data of the IoT sport case for instance the information of football match of a team (the positions, velocities of each player with are recorded in every 20 millisecond).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We use Python to analysis and processing data (calculate the match time, analyst the activities of each player such as time in the bench, time in the pitch, ... )&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We use Tableau to visualize data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recorded at&lt;/strong&gt; PyCon.DE 2017 Karlsruhe: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://de.pycon.org/"&gt;https://de.pycon.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video editing&lt;/strong&gt;: Sebastian Neubauer &amp;amp; Andrei Dan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tools&lt;/strong&gt;: Blender, Avidemux &amp;amp; Sonic Pi&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="devops"></category><category term="analytics"></category><category term="data-science"></category><category term="python"></category></entry><entry><title>Infrastructure as Code with Terraform</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/infrastructure-as-code-with-terraform.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Justyna Janczyszyn</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/infrastructure-as-code-with-terraform.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what is infrastructure as code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;best practices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;benefits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;introduction to terraform&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;practical demo for a sample flask application&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/tramwaj29/iac-with-terraform"&gt;https://github.com/tramwaj29/iac-with-terraform&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="infrastructure"></category><category term="devops"></category><category term="provisioning"></category><category term="terraform"></category><category term="deployment"></category><category term="infrastructure-as-code"></category></entry><entry><title>Taking care of PostgreSQL with Ansible</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/taking-care-of-postgresql-with-ansible.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Rubens Souza</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pycon-italia-2017/taking-care-of-postgresql-with-ansible.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ansible&lt;/strong&gt; is a powerful automation tool written in &lt;strong&gt;Python&lt;/strong&gt;. With
its modules already built for &lt;strong&gt;PostgreSQL&lt;/strong&gt;, we can easily manage the
most advanced open source database, making sure the configuration is
exact in every detail and repeatable as many times as it is needed. In
this talk we will understand how &lt;strong&gt;Ansible&lt;/strong&gt; works, see some of its main
modules for system/cloud administration, and learn how it can be used to
orchestrate &lt;strong&gt;PostgreSQL&lt;/strong&gt; deployments, managing all parts of the
process at ease. A &lt;strong&gt;PostgreSQL&lt;/strong&gt; test environment configuration, using
&lt;strong&gt;Ansible&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Vagrant&lt;/strong&gt;, will be shown as an example.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="postgresql"></category><category term="database"></category><category term="devops"></category><category term="automation"></category><category term="ansible"></category></entry><entry><title>Deploy automatizzato di un progetto Python 3/Django con Ansible</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/deploy-automatizzato-di-un-progetto-python-3django-con-ansible.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Marco Santamaria</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/deploy-automatizzato-di-un-progetto-python-3django-con-ansible.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;La mia applicazione è pronta e funziona senza problemi sulla mia
macchina con il server di sviluppo, ma non ho chiaro come portarla in un
ambiente di produzione. Ci sono parecchi servizi che permettono il
deploy con un solo click, adatti soprattutto a semplici siti, ma essi
non sono pienamente configurabili e nascondono il modo in cui il server
è effettivamente organizzato. Anche se molti usano ingegnose soluzioni
PaaS, vale ancora la pena capire come costruire da zero un ambiente di
produzione con Linux, Python 3, Django e uWSGI. Nel talk questo classico
stack verrà brevemente introdotto e si mostrerà poi come automatizzare
la configurazione e la procedura di deploy con un &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/marco-santamaria/django-%20ansible-deploy"&gt;playbook
Ansible&lt;/a&gt;
che verrà messo a disposizione. Una particolare enfasi verrà data
all’uso di variabili d’ambiente per la configurazione del progetto
seguendo l’approccio delle twelve-factor-app. Inoltre verranno spiegati
i concetti più importanti di Ansible (playbook, ruoli, template, moduli,
inventari).&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="deploy"></category><category term="devops"></category><category term="automation"></category><category term="nginx"></category><category term="ansible"></category><category term="best-practices"></category><category term="django"></category><category term="uwsgi"></category></entry><entry><title>Scaling up to Big Data Devops for Data Science</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pydata-dc-2016/scaling-up-to-big-data-devops-for-data-science.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Marck Vaisman</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-10-08:pydata-dc-2016/scaling-up-to-big-data-devops-for-data-science.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData DC 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scaling up R/Python from a single machine to a cluster environment can be tricky. While there are many tools available that make the launching of a cluster relatively easy, they are not focused or optimized to the specific use case of analytics but mostly on operations. Come and learn about devops tips and tricks to optimize your transition into the big data world as a data scientist.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="big data"></category><category term="Data"></category><category term="data science"></category><category term="devops"></category><category term="scaling"></category><category term="science"></category></entry><entry><title>Getting started with chatops in python with errbot</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pycon-israel-2016/getting-started-with-chatops-in-python-with-errbot.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Guillaume Binet</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-09-20:pycon-israel-2016/getting-started-with-chatops-in-python-with-errbot.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;ChatOps is about bringing your devops tools into your team chatroom. The recent rise of professional chatting services like Slack or Hipchat shows that people are embracing a new way of collaborating. Bringing your tools within those conversations tightens the feedback loop, improves information sharing and onboarding new people in your team. Some common operations implemented with chatops includes deployments, provisioning, monitoring, graphs, development tracking... Those are often implemented with the help of a chat bot like in this presentation Errbot. If your chatops system can be easily extended, for example here in Python, we will see that a team culture can crystallize around it with fun additions. This presentation's goal is to show you how easy it is to get started with chatops in Python, with some technical tips (installation, security, architecture...) but also some social tips to make your company understand better its potential for your team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides available here: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://il.pycon.org/2016/static/sessions/guillaume-binet.pdf"&gt;http://il.pycon.org/2016/static/sessions/guillaume-binet.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="errbot"></category><category term="chatops"></category><category term="devops"></category></entry><entry><title>Building a Production Quality Project in Python</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2015/building-a-production-quality-project-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Clifton Houck</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-10-09:pytexas-2015/building-a-production-quality-project-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This presentation focuses on a variety of tools which can help Python
developers rapidly create production worthy projects by drawing on my
own experience in creating and deploying a Python project called Arsenal
at Rackspace in the space of a few months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arsenal is an open-source service designed to manage and direct a cache
of operating system images on bare-metal nodes. The goal being to
drastically reduce the time it takes to provision a node for
end-users/customers of a bare-metal cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Links to information about arsenal:
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/rackerlabs/arsenal"&gt;https://github.com/rackerlabs/arsenal&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://arsenal.readthedocs.org/en/latest/"&gt;https://arsenal.readthedocs.org/en/latest/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="deployment"></category><category term="devops"></category></entry><entry><title>A Common Scientific Compute Environment for Research and Education</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/scipy-2014/a-common-scientific-compute-environment-for-resea.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-07-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dav Clark</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-09:scipy-2014/a-common-scientific-compute-environment-for-resea.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I provide an overview of the challenges we’ve tackled at UC Berkeley
deploying scientific compute environments in both educational and
research contexts. After a discussion of how these needs can be served
by devops tools like Docker and Ansible, I argue that a coherent,
easy-to-understand philosophy around reproducible compute environments
is fundamental.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the line between developer and researcher becomes ever more blurred,
the challenge of sharing your compute environment with students and
colleagues becomes ever more complex. Large, private organizations have
been grappling with this issue for a while, spawning a great deal of
enthusiasm around tools like Docker, Puppet, Vagrant, and Packer. And
let’s not forget notable python-based upstarts, Ansible and Salt! These
tools can generate immense enthusiasm, followed by the question, “Why
are we doing this?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is that researcher / developers can become overwhelmed by
the complexity and variety inherent in devops tools - all the while
losing sight of the real reason for using these tools: a philosophy of
documenting your research compute environments in a reproducible
fashion, with a focus on scripting as much as is reasonable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At UC Berkeley, members of the D-Lab, the Statistical Compute Facility,
Computer Science and Research IT have organized a project to develop the
Berkeley Common Environment (BCE). I’ll provide an overview of the
challenges we’ve tackled in both educational and research contexts, and
the needs served by the above-mentioned devops tools. In the end, I
argue that a coherent, easy-to-understand philosophy around scientific
compute environments is fundamental - the tools are just a way to make
your collaboration architecture a little easier for the people building
these environments a few times a year. What we should focus on, though,
is end-user experience and research community buy-in.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="devops"></category><category term="reproducible research"></category></entry><entry><title>Practical DevOps</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pycon-de-2012/practical-devops.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2012-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Schlomo Schapiro</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2012-10-31:pycon-de-2012/practical-devops.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;DevOps ist eine aktuelle Bewegung in der IT, die sich zur Aufgabe macht,
ein Umdenken in den klassischen Lagern Entwicklung und Betrieb
einzuleiten. Der Vortrag wirft einen Blick auf die noch junge Bewegung
und zeigt mit Geschichten aus dem wahren Leben, wie sich die agile
Denkweise fortschreiben lässt, die mit SCRUM ins allgemeine Bewusstsein
getreten ist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schlomo gibt einen Überblick über das Thema und berichtet über die
DevOps Erfolge bei der
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.immobilienscout24.de"&gt;ImmobilienScout24&lt;/a&gt;. Nach 2 Jahren
agilem Umdenken in der Entwicklung zeigte sich, dass die klassische
Gewaltenteilung Plan - Build - Run einfach nicht mehr gut funktioniert
weil sich die Anforderungen und Erwartungen sowohl in der Entwicklung
als auch im Betrieb ändern und daher auch eine neue Form der
Zusammenarbeit nahe legen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Die Ideen aus der DevOps Bewegung lassen sich fast überall einsetzen, wo
bisher ein &amp;quot;über den Zaun werfen&amp;quot; gespielt wird und haben das primäre
Ziel, alle Beteiligten gemeinsam an einem Strang ziehen zu lassen. Mit
den Ideen und Erfahrungen aus dem Vortrag lassen sich sicher die ersten
Schritte in die richtige Richtung einleiten.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="agile"></category><category term="devops"></category><category term="kanban"></category><category term="open source"></category><category term="python"></category><category term="scrum"></category><category term="web"></category></entry></feed>