<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_graph.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2018-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Graph Databases: Talking about your Data Relationships with Python</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2018/graph-databases-talking-about-your-data-relationships-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Nicolle Cysneiros</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2018-05-12:pycon-us-2018/graph-databases-talking-about-your-data-relationships-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever considered how many relationships you have in your virtual life? Every friend or page liked on Facebook, each connection in LinkedIn or Twitter account followed is a new relationship not only between two people, but also between their data. In Brazil only, we have 160 millions Facebook users. How can we represent and manipulate all these relationships? Graph Databases are storage systems that use graph structure (nodes and edges) to represent and store data in a semantic way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will begin approaching the challenge in representing relationships in Relational Databases and introducing a more friendly solution using graph. The definition of Graph Database, its pros and cons and some available tools (Neo4J, OrientDB and TitanDB) will be shown during the presentation, as well as how these tools can be integrated with Python.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="graph"></category></entry><entry><title>Analisi dati e grafici con Genropy e Pandas</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2017/analisi-dati-e-grafici-con-genropy-e-pandas.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Francesco Porcari</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-07:pycon-italia-2017/analisi-dati-e-grafici-con-genropy-e-pandas.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Genropy è un framework per la creazione di Single Page Applications che
offre ad utenti e sviluppatori un ambiente di lavoro molto comodo per il
caricamento e la gestione dei dati. In questo talk parleremo degli
strumenti messi a disposizione per l’analisi dei dati e la
rappresentazione grafica, tabellare e in dashboard. Parleremo in
particolare dell’integrazione con Pandas e di come sia facile anche per
un utente non particolarmente esperto generare pivot table, e creare
colonne calcolate e mostrare i risultati come grafici.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="genropy"></category><category term="webapp"></category><category term="pandas"></category><category term="web-development"></category><category term="graph"></category></entry></feed>